<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Espressions</title>
        <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/</link>
        <description>A platform for me to express myself</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 20:47:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <image>
            <title>Espressions</title>
            <url>/Espressions/assets/images/favicon.ico</url>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/</link>
        </image>
        <atom:link href="https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Monster Helper]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/the_monster_helper</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/the_monster_helper</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>SCENE I - The Monsters</h3><p><span class="italic">The curtains open to reveal a makeshift hut made of sticks and bushes at the center of the stage. All around the hut are the burnt ruins of larger huts. Next to the hutt about 3 feet away is a campfire that is providing light to the stage. There is dust and ash everywhere. There is a pale, dark-haired, pointed-ear teenage girl kneeling beside the hut. She is wearing worn-out baggy clothing and a large sunhat. The inside of the hut is visible, and the parts of her skin that are visible are covered in ash. In the hut is a pale, dark-haired, pointed-ear, teenage boy. He is wearing similar attire to the girl and also has ash and dust on his skin. He has clothed bandages wrapping around his left leg. The girl gets on all fours and crawls into the hutt and sits beside the boy. She begins to gently tap him.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Wake up, Nico! Wake up my hermanito!</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS grunts and starts to stretch while laying down.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA CONT.</h4><p>Get up little brother, the sun is down, it's finally nighttime!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Whilst rubbing his eyes</span>)</p><p>Thanks for waking me up hermana. Were you able to get any sleep this morning?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Only a couple of hours. (Pauses to run the calculations in her head.) Yeah, no more than 4 hours.</p></div><p><span class="italic">A sad expression colors NICOLAS' face.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA CONT.</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With a smile on her face</span>)</p><p>It's been hard for me to fall asleep since the vampire hunters attacked our family's settlement five days ago. During the day I feel an overwhelming urge to stay up and keep guard to make sure no more vampire hunters come back around to finish what they started around here.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>I don't care about those savage humans. I just care about your health Lena. You and I both know that's not enough sleep. You're a growing teenager, you need your rest.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I know I know. Tranquilo, don't worry about me Nico. I'll be fine. I just- I just want to make sure you're safe. I don't care what happens to me. You're all I have. I don't want to lose you like we lost Ma and Pa to the vampire hunters five days ago.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS goes to hug his sister.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Te amo, I love you, and I'm not going anywhere. Not without a fight this time. So don't worry about me, I hate seeing my hermana sad and scared, it makes me feel sad and helpless. I want to cheer you up and make you feel like you don't have to carry this burden all by yourself.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Sorry for making you feel that way. I'm just trying my best to be a mother figure to you. I don't know how to do this right. I wish I still had more time with Ma.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Right now, I just want you to be my sister. We can figure out the rest once we get out of this graveyard.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS gives his sister a tight bear hug and begins to stand up and walks with a slight limp out of the hut.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>How's your leg holding up Nico?<br />NICOLAS<br />Like twenty times better!</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS begins to run around the stage.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Looking downcast</span>)</p><p>Sorry, I wasn't able to get us to safety without you getting injured during the vampire hunter's assault.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Hermana, stop apologizing. I hold nothing against you big sis! I'm just glad we are both alive.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS begins doing jumping jacks. SELENA walks out of the hut as well and stands beside him.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Now that you're feeling better, are you ready to start heading over to the location of the Monster Helper Senior Gideon Kiesel?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Yeah! I can't wait to meet Senior Gideon Kiesel!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Me too. Now that Ma, Pa, and the others are gone he is the only adult I can trust. Now help me put out the campfire before we leave.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS go to the edge of the stage to grab an armful of mud to put the fire out with.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Whilst picking up mud</span>)</p><p>I must've been really young the last time we saw him, cause I don't really remember what he looks like.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles whilst picking up mud</span>)</p><p>Of course, you were no older than 2 years old. Luckily for me, I was 6 years old, so even a decade later I still have faint memories of him.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS listen to the crackle of the fire for a moment. They look at the fire and look around themselves at all the debris around them. Then they look back at the fire and take a deep breath. They then throw the mud from their arms into the fireplace and watch as the fire dies down. NICOLAS turns his head to see the gloomy expression on his sister's face. He begins to look up slightly trying to come up with ideas to brighten her mood.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>So what was he like? Why did everyone call him the monster helper?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Because even though he was human, he didn't dedicate his life to hunting us down. Ever since the industrial revolution began, there has been an increase in monster hunters. That's one of the reasons why our pack is nomadic. Unfortunately for us, it looks like we stayed here too long and the humans caught sight of us. Senior Gideon Kiesel is sympathetic and treats our kind with dignity and compassion. He's the man who rescued Ma from some hunters when she was young.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Now that I'm big and strong I can't wait to meet him!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Before we go, let's pay our respects to our deceased family. This will probably be the last time we come here. This place is no longer safe.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>After 6 months of living in this settlement, it was finally starting to feel like home. I hate how we always have to keep moving around, I wish we could stay a little longer.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>The feelings are mutual hermanito, but we have to go. Honestly, we are lucky that we were able to regain our strength five days after the attack.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS walk over to the leftmost side of the stage which contains several piles of dirt with wooden crosses sticking out from all of the piles of dirt. The two somberly stare at the grave. There is silence for a whole minute.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>I still can't believe how fast everything changed. I can't believe they're all gone too.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Sometimes I ask myself, why were we the only ones to survive? That feels so cruel. To live and be surrounded by the dead bodies of everyone you loved.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Breaks out in tears</span>)</p><p>They think we are monsters, but we have done nothing! We have done nothing to them.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Even though that's true, you know why the humans attacked our village. Our ancestors really made a negative impact on them. They fed off them. They kidnapped their loved ones and infected them with our disease. Even though our family and pack have sworn to the Chupacabra Oath to only feast on animals, the humans can't tell the difference between us and human-feasting fiends like the Glouls.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Starts to pout</span>)</p><p>We do not have a disease.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Come on hermanito. If we weren't diseased why does mother nature hate us? We can't go into the sun without burning. We need a constant supply of the blood of living things to survive.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS covers her pointy ears and shakes her head frantically.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Sometimes you sound like them! You are a vampire, be proud of our ancestry!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I never said I wasn't, I was just pointing out the facts. It's not a surprise that the humans attacked us. Now that they have made technological advancements they feel ready to finally get their revenge.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>But still, why attack a peaceful village? We were defenseless.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>That's exactly the reason why they attacked this village. It was to send a message to the more hostile vampire factions. Get in line. Or see what becomes of your home, your family, your possessions.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Curse those factions. I don't even consider them as one of us. Those stupid bottom-feeding ghouls. Their refusal to let go of such a dated practice has cost us everything. And for what? Human blood is disgusting.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I don't disagree. When I asked our great great great grandfather when his generation stopped drinking human blood, he said partially it was because humans started living like drugged pigs. Filling their bodies with sugar and weird chemicals Their blood became a repulsive chemical soup that was making us sick.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Whilst running his eyes</span>)</p><p>And yet those ghouls continue to eat that up.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS share a laugh.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Well, I think it's time we start heading over to Senior Kiesel's house. From what I remember it's a solid 20 miles away. I think we can easily cover more ground if we transform into our dog form to give us a boost of stamina.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Alright! Let's go to Senior Kiesel's house!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Looking seriously into her brother's eyes</span>)</p><p>And if we run into those vampire hunters again, I promise hermanito, I won't let those monsters hurt you.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles</span>)</p><p>I know you won't.</p></div><h3>SCENE II - The Hunters</h3><p><span class="italic">The curtains open to the interior of a log cabin. The walls reflect the warm orangish color of the tungsten bulbs that hang from the tall ceiling. The oak floor is clothed with the hide of a wolf. There are two large wooden desks in the room. One is by the door which is facing west of the stage. There is another desk on the eastern side of the stage. There is a fancy curved rocking chair at this desk. This well-filed and organized desk is free of clutter and mess. And at this desk is seated a man approaching middle age. FELIX WOLF. He is wearing his leather boots and gloves. His trench coat is still on him. His cowboy hat is still hugging his forward head. He has a Baselard, a short sword, in his left hand. In his right hand, he has a sandpaper cloth. He is sharpening his weapon. Above his head is a poster of the legendary vampire hunter Roland Stone. The cabin door swings open and in walks a woman in her late twenties. She is wearing knee-high boots, vintage mom jeans, and an oversized sweatshirt. She has large hooped earrings dangling from her ear lobes. Her dirty blond hair is done in a bob style. She is holding an envelope in her left hand, and a ridiculously large shopping bag in her right.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>You're still in that same chair, sharpening that same knife huh-</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>It's called a Baselard, and issa sword, not a knife.</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX briefly looks up at NADIA and then immediately goes back to sharpening his blade.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Potato, potahto. I get this is our job and all and that we have to be good at it, but come on man, live a little. You have got to stop rejecting my offers to go shopping together.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Life's more than blowing money on material possessions.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Acts shocked and speaking sarcastically</span>)</p><p>Ouch, (puts hand with the shopping bag over her chest) that really hurts Fe.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>I thought I told ya not to call me that.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Come on Fe, lighten up, we've been co-workers for 8 years now. I think we should be on a nickname basis now.</p></div><p><span class="italic">Felix sighs, puts the knife blade down along with a cleaning wipe, and gets up out of his chair.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Fine, you're lucky I'm in a good mood. What was that childish name you wanted me to call ya... (Begins scratching head) Was it Naddy?</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA puts the shopping bag on the floor and the envelope on a nearby desk, while sighing.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>No, it was Dia. Come on Fe, you're only 32 yet you act like a decrepit old man sometimes. I literally have to constantly remind you to call me Dia.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Watch your tone wit me Nadia.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>DIA! Come on, we are supposed to be on a nickname basis!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Signs and facepalms</span>)</p><p>Whatever, anyways what did you waste your cut of the commission on this time (He points to NADIA's bags), and what's with those papers ya walked in with?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Grabbing the shopping bag and making a puppy dog face</span>)</p><p>Oh, this thingy?! Remember that new pair of heels that Baelina Williams just released?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Don't tell me you actually wasted money on those ugly things. (Sighs and slaps his face)</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>I DID!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Those are like a thousand dollars. That's your whole cut of the commission. Ya need to be more wise with your money.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Come down, you act like I'm going to go broke. Vampires and monsters aren't going extinct yet. Humanity has only recently started killing them off. And as long as there are monsters wreaking havoc on humanity, there will be some fool desperate enough to pay us to kill them off.</p></div><p><span class="italic">She smiles and begins to pull out the most hideous fuzzy shoes you've ever seen</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>This is more than just a job ya know.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">In a mocking tone</span>)</p><p>Yeah, yeah, it's more than a job, it's a privilege, an honorable service to our country. (<span class="italic">Speaking normally</span>) You've told me at least a thousand times.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>And yet it seems I am not able to penetrate the stubborn soil that is your skull.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Are you trying to hurt my feelings today? If you keep going, you might actually make me cry this time (She smirks).</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Sighs and slaps his face</span>)</p><p>I'm not trying to hurt your feelings. It's just I wish ya would take this job more seriously. The foes we fight are not to be trifled with.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>The vampires? Those vermin don't frighten me at all. I just see them as no more than pests that we get paid the big bucks to deal with.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Is that all you see of this job? We're a bunch of overpaid exterminators?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>You said it, not me. But I totally agree.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>I fear for your generation.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>You know you're only four years apart from me, right? We are from the same generation, dummy.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Vampires are more than just mosquitos and ticks. They are vicious cold-blooded heartless freaks of nature. If we don't kill them they will kill us. We have centuries of history to show us that. They are cunning and smart. Those mutts possess sentience and a form of intelligence that allows those monsters to compete with us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Okay and?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>I lost my mother to those beasts. For centuries, all of humanity has been on the losing side of the fight for dominance and security against these demonic creatures for far too long. Thanks to the industrial revolution and our technological advancements we can finely hurt them back. And I will refuse to sit back and watch a generation of careless people grow up. A naive person has a false sense of safety. You feel safe and like this job is light work because of people like me. People like the legendary Roland Stone, who sacrifice their lives to make the world a better place.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>You really don't know much about me after all these years. Do you pay attention to anything I say? I'm not just some naive girl. I grew up with no parents because vampires were killed. I had to raise my two baby brothers all by myself by begging for scraps. When I learned how lucrative and rewarding the vampire hunting industry was, I trained myself to become a cleaning machine so that my brothers and I could have an easy life because our childhood was a pile of crap!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>I'm sorry, sorry for making so many assumptions about you. I'm so used to watching you acting so vain, I forget about the life you came from.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Dang Fe, the stone-hearted man is finally apologizing, I must have really hit a soft spot for you. I'm not used to seeing you emote.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>It just pains me to see you act careless. You almost hurt yourself badly two days ago.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Yeah, but I didn't get hurt (smiles), you forgot I graduated top of my class from the academy. I know I plan it too close for your comfort, but it's the only way I can keep myself from getting bored. Our tools make this job easier.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Whatever, just be more careful. You know how much I've been through, I lost my loved ones to those monsters so when I see you being dainty and giddy on the battlefield it triggers memories of my dying family for me.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Putting hands on her cheeks</span>)</p><p>Awww Fe, did you finally admit that you love me?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With an emotionless expression</span>)</p><p>Ya are literally every red flag I avoid in women.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Laughs</span>)</p><p>Whatever you say Fe, I know you find me irresistible. I mean who wouldn't?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Whatever Dia, anyways ya never answered my question. What's with the envelope?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Awww, you finally called me by my nickname. Looks like pouring your heart out was all you needed.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Can ya stay focused for once?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Fine fine, calm down buzz kill. While I was shopping, I got a call to pick up from the Mayor's security about a new assignment.</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX's eyes come back to life, he leans forward in his chair eager to hear what NADIA has to say.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Apparently, people have spotted smoke coming from the ruins of the vampire village we attacked 2 days ago. They think we messed up a spot and that there might be survivors trying to regain their strength. We are to right to the ruins and kill any survivors immediately.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With an unamused expression</span>)</p><p>I told ya not to leave any stone left unturned.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Don't put all the blame on me Fe, you said it yourself, these cunning vermin are somehow as smart as us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Whatever, grab up stuff, and get ready by 5. I'll get our rides ready.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>5 minutes is not enough time! I need to shower and fix my hair and iron my clothes.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Ya have 5 minutes, if those vampires harm any of the towns folk you'll have their blood on your hands.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Fine buzz kill. But believe me, when we get back home, I am going to hog the shower for at least two hours to make you suffer in your sweat and stinkiness like you're doing to me now.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Sigh and shakes his head</span>)</p><p>You're so childish.</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX gets up and heads out the door. NADIA pouts and crosses her arms.</span></p><h3>SCENE III - The Hunt</h3><p><span class="italic">The curtains open to reveal the woods. The background of the stage is populated by trees. The night sky is dark yet shines bright thanks to the illuminations of numerous stars. The middle of the stages is clear of trees. In comes the orphans from the east onto the stage. They are in dog customs and walking on all fours.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Are we there yet?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I'd say about 10 more minutes.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Hey Lena, do you hear that?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I don't hear anything suspicious, but I am picking up a familiar perfume. Lavender.</p></div><div class="dual-dialogue"><div class="dialogue left"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>OH NO, IT'S THE HUNTERS!</p></div><div class="dialogue right"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>OH NO, IT'S THE HUNTERS!</p></div></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX and NADIA rush onto the stage.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Ya cursed beasts sure have a good sense of smell, but that won't save ya.</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX unsheathes his blade and runs towards SELENA.</span></p><p><span class="italic">SELENA swings her tail and goes to punch her face.</span></p><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS catches his fist through!</span></p><p><span class="italic">SELENA uses the opportunity to swing her body and knock FELIX over with her tail</span></p><p><span class="italic">NADIA laughs at FELIX.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Are ya just going to stand there and watch me get my butt whooped? Come over and help me, lazy bones.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA dashes toward the vampire orphans. She pulls out short daggers from her waist.</span></p><p><span class="italic">She swings her arms with precision.</span></p><p><span class="italic">Her swings make contact with SELENA's scales, but SELENA is unfazed.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Nico, run off into the trees, and I'll take care of this!</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS hops off SELENA's back and runs off the stage.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Oh no ya don't</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX begins to chase after NICOLAS but gets his leg grabbed by SELENA.</span></p><p><span class="italic">SELENA yanks him to the ground and begins to pin him in place. She goes to bite him.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>DO IT! I dare you. Ya freak of nature!</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA is taken aback and hesitates.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I'm not a freak of nature!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>You say that, yet you are in the form of a dog with a terrible case of mange.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA looks at her arms.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I'm only in this form to protect my brother from you monsters. You guys took everything from us, and yet you aren't satisfied!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Look who's talking. The cursed blood-sucking demon calling whose kind has haunted humanity for years is accusing me of doing the same. What I am doing is justice. Did your kind really think they could get away with their crimes?</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA grabs SELENA from behind and throws her to the ground.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Starts to get up</span>)</p><p>Ya sure took your time</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>I'm just trying to process how you're struggling to end a little kid.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>You know these creatures are stronger than they look!</p></div><p>I</p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Stop calling me a creature!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>You won't want me to lie to your face kid? Sorry, but I speak my mind 24/7 and the truth is you're a disgusting vermin. We are not the same. You are an abomination, a freak of nature.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA begins to shed a tear.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Did Dia hurt your feelings?</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA goes to bite NADIA but gets punched in the throat by FELIX. SELENA stumbles back a bit. She is staggered.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Ya vampires are creatures of lust and greed. Your ancestors couldn't accept reality. They couldn't accept death. They tried to cheat it and lost their humanity. Children of the cursed. Even the sun can't stand the sight of you. Mother Nature saw how your kind persecuted us, and under her sheltering, we have progressed and made numerous technological advancements. Your days are numbered. Soon your kind will be extinct like the dinosaurs!</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX pulls a gun out of his boot hilt.</span></p><p><span class="italic">SELENA coming to her senses.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>But we did nothing to you! We were a peaceful village! We lived off the deer in the area. We didn't harm a single human.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Ya think we don't understand the game you're planning? The peaceful pacifism ya live in is a charade. Ya want us to let our guard down?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Nonsense!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>DON'T TALK TO ME ABOUT NONSENSE. IT WAS A SUPPOSED PEACEFUL VAMPIRE THAT KILLED MY MOTHER RIGHT IN FRONT OF MY EYES. THAT IS WHY Y'ALL MUST BURN. YA CREATURES HAVE NO HEART. DECEPTION IN THE ONLY LANGUAGE YA SPEAKS!</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX loads his gun with silver bullets.</span></p><p><span class="italic">NADIA puts her daggers back in her boot hilts.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>You really wear your heart on your sleeves.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Shut up and go pin her while I ready my shot.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA runs toward SELENA pulling out her twin daggers again.</span></p><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS runs on the stage and bashes into NADIA from behind, sending her flying into a tree and knocking her out.</span></p><p><span class="italic">FELIX is startled as this all happens so fast.</span></p><p><span class="italic">SELENA uses the opportunity to slam her claws at FELIX.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>DUCK NICO!</p></div><p><span class="italic">As NICOLAS ducks, SELENA swings her claws and knocks FELIX to the ground hard. FELIX Passes out.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Let's get out of here! Quick get on my back!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>You're not going to kill them?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>And proved their point? They think we are heartless monsters. But not, we are pacifists who only engage in self-defense.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>You're right.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>This is how Padre would've handled things.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NICOLAS hops on SELENA's back and the two exit the stage.</span></p><h3>SCENE IV - The Helper</h3><p><span class="italic">The curtains open to reveal the stage split in half. On the left-hand side of the stage is a living room. The wall containing the living door is placed in the center of the stage. The living room is decorated with hundreds of colorful books supported by beautiful wooden shelves with flowers carved in the corners. There is a bright red couch at the leftmost end of the stage, facing toward a fireplace. An old rugged man is sitting on the couch. He is wearing a collared polo and cargo shorts. In his hands is a necklace. On it are numerous beads, each with a name carved on it. He has a very solemn expression on his face.</span></p><p><span class="italic">On the right side of the stage are trees and bushes. The wilderness, the great unknown. Who knows the creatures that lurk in these woods?</span></p><p><span class="italic">Onto the stage comes SELENA wearing a wolf costume, and on her back is NICOLAS. SELENA talks of her wolf costume and stretches her limbs.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>We are finally here! We barely made it alive.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>You can say that again.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Now I want you to be on your best behavior okay? Don't embarrass me in front of Senior Kiesel.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Ew, you sound like Ma right now.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA smiles and playful hits NICOLAS on the arm again. NICOLAS rubs his arm again to soothe the pain. ROLAND STONE hears the commotion going on outside and gets up and heads towards the door. He turns the knob and opens it. SELENA and NICOLAS are started by his appearance.</span></p><div class="dual-dialogue"><div class="dialogue left"><h4>SELENA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With big cheery smiles</span>)</p><p>You must be Senior Gideon Kiesel!</p></div><div class="dialogue right"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With big cheery smiles</span>)</p><p>You must be Senior Gideon Kiesel!</p></div></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>I was, I stopped going by that name years ago. I just go by Roland G. K. Stone now. And who do you two happen to be?</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS look at each other in confusion and there back to ROLAND who is stepping outside his house and closing the door behind him. He stands there in front of the do with his hands in his pockets.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>It's me Selena Lockwood and this is my brother Nicolas Lockwood. Remember us? We are the children of Sierra Katherines Lockwood.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Sniffles</span>)</p><p>So Sierra ended up safe after all. I haven't seen her or you two in over a decade. How is the family?</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENE and NICOLAS look down to the ground. The stage is dead silent for 30 seconds.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>She's dead, isn't she?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Y-yes.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Sighs</span>)</p><p>It was the hunters, wasn't it?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Yes, Senior Stone! They destroyed everything! The whole village! They took away our friends and family! And they are after us right now!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>They figured out we survived.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>So you brought them to my house?! (<span class="italic">Looks outside his door frantically</span>). Are you trying to get me killed? I thought I told your kind that I was retiring from this lifestyle. I'm getting too old and weak to hide from the establishment. (<span class="italic">Sighs and facepalms</span>). Quick get inside.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS enter ROLAND's house.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Are you going to help us, Senior Stone?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Please have mercy on us and help us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Our Madre always spoke kindly of you. She said amongst all of humanity you were one of the few to possess a sound mind and a compassionate heart.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Look, I want to help you guys and all. But I'm getting too weak. I've had too many close calls in my youth. I can't keep this up any longer. I protect you for the night, but after that, you're on your own.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Too many close calls? Have the hunters been after you too?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>No. Not necessarily.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Then what do you mean you've had too many close calls? Why did you retire?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Because. I'm a monster hunter-</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS begin to hyperventilate.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Calm down you two and let me finish my sentence. I'm a monster hunter in the eyes of the law. You see, it is illegal to do what I've been doing for decades, harboring refugee monsters. I was only ever able to escape suspicion thanks to my cover as a monster hunter.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>You should've gotten to that part sooner! Are you trying to give me a heart attack?!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>For goodness sake, no. Sorry to scare you two.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>It's alright Senior Stone. I think you can make it up to us by protecting us like you did our people in the past.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Nico, don't be pushy. (Turns to ROLAND) Sorry about his behavior, he can be a little... demanding sometimes.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>You two remind me so much of your parents. These used to bricker all the time back when they were under my care. I'm truly sorry for your loss. They were precious in my heart, truly.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>What made you get into helping our kind?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>And what made you stop?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>It's cliche. But the answer is love.</p></div><div class="dual-dialogue"><div class="dialogue left"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>You fell in love with a vampire?!</p></div><div class="dialogue right"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>You fell in love with a vampire?!</p></div></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>I was a young man, (Stroking his gray beard). I was once blinded by society's point of view. That vampires were demonic creatures of the night. That they were heartless blood-sucking immoral monsters. I had friends who all had relatives that had been victims of vampire attacks.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Grumbles</span>)</p><p>Ghouls. It was those stupid ghouls, wasn't it?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>Yeah. It was. I didn't know that at the time. I didn't know that there were such diverse opinions on how to live within the vampire race.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Crossing her arms</span>)</p><p>Yeah, we don't all think the same.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>You're right my friend, and it took falling in love to realize that. I joined the vampire-hunting division of the local militia. And I was good at it. I must've killed at least 50 vampires before I realize how wrong my actions are.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS gasp.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>It was a cold dark night when I met Lucile. I was sent to investigate strange activity coming from an abandoned hospital. When I got there I saw a vampire caring for injured humans. Our undesirables. She, their enemy, was having compassion on them and nursed them back to love. It was then I realized everything I knew about these supposed heartless creatures was wrong.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>This doesn't have a happy ending, does it?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Depends on how you see it, my friend. I couldn't kill Lucile. She staged her death and took her in under my care. Using my status I was able to get the government to show compassion to the very undesirables they abandon. Over the years I spent with her, she taught me the history of your people. How mother nature herself cursed you guys with immortality at the cost of your humanity. You guys could live forever but needed an appetite for blood to sustain it. And when I realized that a majority of vampires decided to either live off just animal blood even though it was the most repulsive taste imaginable, or grow weak and die a natural death after decades of slowly decaying. It was then I realized we have killed more innocent pacifists.<br />Lucile was the one who encouraged me to become an advocate for the vampires. But I was too much of a coward to do it in the light. So under the guise of being publically known as Roland Stone the great Monster Hunter. I secretly became the Monster Helper. I took on more and more cases. If I could get to the vampires before my colleagues, I could fake their deaths and get them to safety. And for decades it worked.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I don't get it then what happened to Lucile? Why did you retire?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>We lived happily for 20 years. She was my partner in crime. I wanted us to start a family. But she didn't want to birth cursed children. I told her that I didn't care, we could make it work. I'd love those kids no matter their condition. But she feared for my reputation, she feared what would happen if it were discovered that the famous Vampire Hunter had half-vampire children. Over time people began to get suspicious of me. There were discrepancies in my work.<br />She knew that if I was caught I'd be charged with treason against my own race and given the death penalty. So she staged an attack on my workplace to try to vindicate my<br />crumbling reputation. She didn't tell me about it in advance. She orchestrated her death to be at my hands in front of my co-workers. She died in my arms. My co-workers were amazed by my cruelty in slaying her. It removed all their suspicions. But it wasn't me. I was under her hypnosis. She promised she would never take advantage of me in that manner. She lied. But she did it to protect me.<br />When I got home, broken and in tears, I discovered her letter. She was happy to die by my hands because she knew there was no hate in my heart. After that day I retired. At 45 years old I just wanted to be alone. I had taken the life of my love. I didn't want to see another human or vampire. I didn't want to be another cog in the machine that led to her death.<br />I'm sorry but I just can't help you guys. I've barely escaped suspicion all these years. I just want to be allowed and mourn Lucile.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Do you think this is the life she wanted for you?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>My friend, I've given the past of my years to the cause of protecting your kind.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>And I'm grateful. But there is still injustice in the world against our people. And you're one of the few people with a sound mind. With all due respect Senior Stone. Lucile died because you wanted to live a double life. You can't serve two masters. There comes a point in your life where you have to choose a side and plant your foot down. So what's it going to be?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>I can't believe a child is trying to give me advice.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>I'm 57 years old. By human standards that's quite old.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>Lucile was just as afraid as me. I'm living the very life she wanted me to live. Sheltered and in hiding. I'm living how she lived. In fear. The only life she knew.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>And look at where it has brought you too. Why must we continue to live like this?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Sighs</span>)</p><p>Nicolas, your sister is wise beyond her appearances. Fine, I'll help you guys.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smirking</span>)</p><p>Yeah, she gets it from me.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA hits him on the arm. The two siblings laugh.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Not just for tonight right Senior Stone?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Not just for tonight. You've challenged me. I'll come out of retirement to help you guys grow old to see adulthood. You guys won't have to hide after me and Lucile did.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Awesome! So what's the plan, Senior Stone?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With a large smile</span>)</p><p>First, we hide.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ROLAND chuckles.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Is the plan really to run and hide for all your mortal life still? I thought we weren't going to do that.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Nico, quit complaining, the man is doing the best he can to help us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Ouch, and no, we won't forever. I just needed to get those knucklehead hunters off your trail. Now that they are gone we can regroup. From now you two will be my children. I'll<br />take care of you two as my own. We will go to the move out of town and head to the capital and start there. I'll bring to light my history with Lucile, the nature of your village. Together we will make peace between our kinds.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>But we still can't be in the sunlight for too long, and the people will try to have us killed.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Not if they think you are my children. I have too much respect for that.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>You do realize that you are about to lose it all when you get honest with the public</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Oh I know I'll lose a ton of respect from people with an anti-vampire ideology, but we will gain a new support group. With my big name backing the cause, more people will feel motivated to join us.</p></div><div class="dual-dialogue"><div class="dialogue left"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Thank you for protecting us.</p></div><div class="dialogue right"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p>Thank you for protecting us.</p></div></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Hugs the orphans</span>)</p><p>Thank you for helping me see things more clearly.</p></div><h3>SCENE V - The Confrontation</h3><p><span class="italic">The curtains open to reveal the stage split in two. On the right side are the woods. Trees and brushes and darkness decorate that side of the stage. On the left-hand side is ROLAND's living room. In the living room are ROLAND STONE, SELENA LOCKWOOD, and NICOLAS LOCKWOOD. On the right-hand side of the stage, FELIX and NADIA enter on their horse.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Are you sure this is where they went?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>According to my vampire tracker, this is where their scent traveled to. It stops here. They must still be alive.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>The lights are on. Do you think someone was home?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Ya better hope on your life that no one is home.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Should we barge through the door and break through a window?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>You can take the window, I'll take the door.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Alright partner, let's go.</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX begins to run towards the door and flies in because the door wasn't closed properly.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Ouch (He tries to stop his head from spinning).</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA begins breaking out in laughter.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Begins to regain consciousness</span>)</p><p>Wait a minute, y-you're the legendary Roland Stone! The greatest vampire slayer to ever live. Over 100 of those vermin were killed at his feet! The reason I became a vampire hunter!</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX notices two pale figures right behind ROLAND and his jaw drops to the ground.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX CONT.</h4><p>WAIT A DAMN MINUTE!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Walking through the door</span>)</p><p>What's wrong Fe, is that your inner stan short-circuiting your brain?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>No! It's the two vampire twerps we've been hunting this whole time. Why are they in the house of the legendary vampire hunter? And why aren't they dead at his hands?!</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA and NICOLAS coward behind ROLAND's back.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Now, now, slow down Son. Let me explain what is going on here.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Yeah, what's going on? Because if I weren't mistaken it looks like you're actually protecting these vermin.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Well, are you a smart one daughter, I am protecting these children.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>WHY?! You're supposed to be Roland Stone the legendary vampire hunter? Have you gone senile in your old age? Step aside let me end the lives of those beasts before they harm you and more. They must have drained a lot of your blood which is likely the cause of all this nonsense that you've been spewing.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>I assure you, I may be old and starting to decay, but I'm still sharp as a tact. Please put your weapons down and let's have a civil conversation.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>Fine, I'd love to hear the explanation behind my hero committing an act of treason.</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX and NADIA drop their weapons.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Everything you two know about me is a lie. I gave up on vampire hunter long into my career. When I met my late wife, a vampire, I learned that those (Makes air quotes with his fingers) monsters, as society puts it, aren't actually heartless beasts. They too are compassionate. Not all of them survive off the blood of humans.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>That's right! I was trying to tell you guys, but you kept attacking us! We follow the way of the chupacabra and live off of only animal blood.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>You shut ya mouth! I don't wanna hear from you mutt. Roland! I can't believe what you're saying. When my parents died at the hand of vampires, I built my whole life on your fame. Your reputation was like a father figure to me. You're telling me I built my life on lies?!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>I'm sorry for failing to live up to the version of me you had on a pedestal. In reality, all my life I was a coward. I started hunting vampires because I didn't want to deal with the trauma and hurt from my childhood, and when I learned not all vampires are evil monsters, I was too cowardly to publically stand up for them. Well, these kids have helped me understand my late wife more than I did when she was alive. I'm done being a coward. I'm going to stand for what I believe in.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>I'm gonna turn ya in to the authorities! This is a dangerous ideology! Vampires are heartless killers that can't be trusted.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Poking her head from behind ROLAND's back</span>)</p><p>Again you're wrong. Our pack which you two destroyed, for six months settled near that village and never attacked a single human being. We only ever went from cattle on farms with excess cattle and after unclaimed stray animals.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>So what, you vermin are nothing but glorified mosquitos and need to be crushed like such. You guys are pests.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Poking his head from ROLAND's back whilst trembling</span>)</p><p>And what makes you humans so different from us? You guys live off the land and drain it of its resources. You cut down forests, and kill whole ecosystems, just so you can live comfortably. All we ever do you go after animals. We do the bare minimum to survive, yet you lump us with vampires that have the human trait of greed and lust for power.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>The kids make a good point. Don't you two see. Everything we know about the vampires is wrong. There's more nuisance to them.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>How do ya explain the death of my parents?!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Just like there exist criminals and bad apples among us, it is the same for vampires. Should we really write off an entire group of people because of the sins of a few?</p></div><p><span class="italic">FELIX falls to his knees and begins to start pulling at his hair.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p>I dedicated my life to following a lie.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>So glad I never looked up to anyone. See Fe, this is what you get for idolizing a man.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Daughter-</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Would you stop calling me that? I don't care about your cause. Unlike my friend here, I never worshiped the ground you walked on. To be honest I don't really care about the vermin all that much. Sure they killed my parents. But I was so young I barely remember them anyways. All I care about is getting paid so my brothers and I can live comfortably.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>So, what are you going to do about this? Are you going to expose us to authorities? Are you going to feed the cycle of hatred behind us and the peaceful vampires?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p>Like I said, old man. I don't care. I'm not completely heartless so I'll keep my mouth shut. But I won't join you. I'm not giving up my life of comfort.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA picks up her weapons and sheaves them back on her person. She starts making her way out the door. ROLAND turns to FELIX.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>Son, I know this is a lot for you to take in right now. But please don't try to stop what I want to accomplish. In my old age, I've finally found the courage to fight for what I believe in. Join us, let me undo all the lies that you have learned thanks to people like me. Let me teach you and show you that you, like young me, are wrong about vampires.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Starting to come to tears</span>)</p><p>How can I turn my back on this lifestyle? That's all I know. How am I supposed to navigate this? I can't unsee the fact that I built my life on a lie.</p></div><p><span class="italic">SELENA, feeling bold, walks up the FELIX and puts her arm on his back.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA</h4><p>Senior Felix, I totally understand, being confused and unsure of which way to go after a managed change occurs in life. I don't hold it against you for killing my family, your judgment was clouded by hatred. When I lost all my loved ones, my whole world was turned upside down and I had to learn how to navigate the new position life has placed me. All I had was my brother and I just want to protect and help him live in a world that is so chaotic. I know this is a lot for you. I know when you see me, you see a face similar<br />to the one that took everything from you. But if I care to look at the man that took everything from me and still forgive him, can you be willing to do the same?</p></div><p><span class="italic">With tears in his eyes, FELIX hugs SELENA.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>SELENA CONT.</h4><p>No llores, don't cry Senior.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA walks back into the living room. All eyes turn to her. Her mascara is starting to run.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADIA</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">On the verge of tears</span>)</p><p>Okay, you got to me. Just like you girlie, all I care about is making life easier for my brothers. I'm not as selfless as you. I didn't want to give up my comfortable life. But hearing about how you're learning to navigate life with your brother without your parents, that sounds too much like my story. As I was walking out the door it finally dawned on me, my love of money has made me a cold-hearted monster. I was doing this for my own self-interest and hiding behind my brothers to make my actions look good. So I'm quitting being a vampire hunter. When our bosses don't hear from us, they will assume we died on the battlefield as that's a common occurrence in this line of work. Any living relative of me and Fe will receive money from the government. I'll lose my source of income, but I guess I deserve it for being such a jerk. I'm sorry girlie, sorry little boy. Let me make it up to you by joining you all and being the mother figure that I took away from you.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADIA breaks down in tears and NICOLAS and SELENA run to embrace her. FELIX gets up and ROLAND comes to put his arm around us.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p>I bet you didn't think today would be the day your life hit a crossroads that would forever change the man you become.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Pensively</span>)</p><p>In a weird way, the fire that I inflicted on their family's settlement, it feels like I'm growing through it myself. It hurts. But I feel the hatred and bitterness in my heart being burned off, leaving compassion and empathy in my heart. I didn't realize that in my bitterness and rage, I myself became a monster too.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ROLAND</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With a smile</span>)</p><p>Good, I finally see the world more clearly. Now that your heart has opened, let's do this.<br />Let's change the world and bring peace between humans and monsters.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>FELIX NADIA SELENA NICOLAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">In tears whilst embracing each other in a hug</span>)</p><p>Lets!</p></div><h3>END</h3>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Healer's Child]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/healers_child</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/healers_child</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>SCENE ONE OPENS</h3><p><span class="italic">The stage is a barren wilderness. Cacti populate the stage.</span></p><p><span class="italic">NADINE AMARA walks onto the stage and onto the spinning floor. As she hopes it it begins to spin allowing her to walk in place. She is wearing a brown backpack. She is wearing armor designed for mobility, allowing her to move swiftly and strike quickly. She has cargo shorts on that provide ample storage for necessary items, indicating she is well-prepared and resourceful. She is golden brown hair down to her shoulders. She has a walking stick in her right arm.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>I never thought I'd make it this far. I can almost see the great chasm from here. He was right. The Great Healer has proven himself faithful and right once again.</p></div><p><span class="italic">She takes an amount to wipe the sweat off her brow. She pauses to look at her arm which is covered in stone.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE (CONT.)</h4><p>Everything I see the stones, the remains of my former life, I remember where I was before he found me.</p></div><p><span class="italic">A tear of joy begins to fall from her eye.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE (CONT.)</h4><p>I never want to get back to that. Feeling like a prisoner in my own body. Feeling stuck and enslaved. I don't care that my body is no longer shielded from the glaring sun or the harsh arid air. I'd rather suffer in freedom, they remain comfortable in a prison of my own making.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>UNKNOWN VOICE</h4><p>Woe is me. I have no love. No one cares about me.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADINE turns her head frantically to try to locate the source of this unknown voice.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>UNKNOWN VOICE</h4><p>Woe is me. I have no love. No one cares about me.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>Who said that? Is anyone there?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>UNKNOWN VOICE</h4><p>Woe is me. I have no love. No one cares about me.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADINE locates the source of the voice and runs towards it.</span></p><p><span class="italic">JEREMIAH LIRMARA walks onto the stage. He is clothed head to toe in stone. There is a tiny crack in his stone exterior that allows us to see his tear-filled eyes.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH LIRMARA</h4><p>Woe is me. I have no love. No one cares about me.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>Don't say that!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Moans</span>)</p><p>What? Don't say the truth. Woe is me. I no one. I have no love. No one cares about me.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>No, that is not true at all!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH</h4><p>What makes you say it is not true? Look at me I'm a monster. Woe is me. I have no love. No one cares about me.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>Because I was once like you!</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADINE lifts up her stone-covered arm.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE (CONT.)</h4><p>I was without hope. I was born as a stone monster just like you. I lived a life of comfort in my pain and sorrow. Bitternish was my food and complaining was my drink. I couldn't see life getting any better.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH</h4><p>What changed? How did you get free of the great curse that affects all of us?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>I did nothing. It was all the work of the Great Healer.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH</h4><p>The Great Healer? Who are they and where can I meet them? I want to be free from this curse.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>He is the one who lives on the other hand of the Great Chasm. He prepared a feast for his creation but no one came. The great curse has held us all in bondage. So he came down to rescue us from the curse. He is a busy name so he doesn't stay in one place for long. But he has given us a map and his power and has sent us on our way.</p></div><p><span class="italic">The faint sound of rocks cracking can be heard. NADINE looks at her stone-covered hands. A chunk of stone falls off.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE (CONT.)</h4><p>If you want, I can free you too. But just so you know life wants to be easy. In fact, it will hurt. You will be more vulnerable and weak. But if you endure it will on be worth it. The Healer gives us enough strength for each day.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH</h4><p>I WANT TO BE FREE.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p>It is finished then.</p></div><p><span class="italic">NADINE grabs JEREMIAH and pulls him out of his stone suit. A shirtless and slimy JEREMIAH falls out of the stone suit. He is pink and slimy like a newborn baby.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH</h4><p>It hurts. Everything hurts. I feel the course sand prickling my knees. I feel the harsh wind scratching my skin. The sun is too bright for my fleshly eyes. Everything hurts. But I'm free, free at last.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles</span>)</p><p>Welcome brother. This is the start of your journey. Don't worry, you won't walk the path alone. I am here for you, and others have gone before us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>JEREMIAH</h4><p>There are others?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>NADINE</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles and pats his shoulder</span>)</p><p>More than you can imagine. Now let us go find you a lake or pound to wash you off.</p></div><h3>SCENE ONE ENDS</h3>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Break Out - v3]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/breakout-v3</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/breakout-v3</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>I'll wash, you dry.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>You sure about that? You washed yesterday, and the day before that, and the day before that. Heck when was the last time you let someone else wash?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>No offense older brother, but you and your little sister are terrible dishwashers. You two always miss a spot and leave oil stained on the supposedly washed dishes.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>I'm still a kid and learning how to wash dishes, big bro. You're a whole grown man. What's your excuse?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Why are you two tagging up on me all of a sudden?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Oh, get over yourself. I told you not to take often to what I was going to say. Just take care of drying the dishes. You pretty good at that</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Sighs</span>)</p><p>Fine. Gimmie those. (<span class="italic">Grabs a dray rag and extends his arm to receive the dish that CHARLOTTE just finished washing</span>).</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>I can't believe we got promoted to this big unit. We have our own kitchenette now! We don't have to eat in that cold gloomy dining hall anymore. This game is so much fun. All we have to do is just go pew pew pew and we get big rewards</p></div><p><span class="italic">THOMAS looks over at KANSAS who is planning with crayons and paper, a look of concern paints his face.</span></p><p><span class="italic">CHARLOTTE notices the look on his face and whispers to him.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>You think she'll turn out okay?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Huh? What do you mean by that? Are you talking about Kansas?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Duh. I see the way you look at her when she talks. I see you look at my the same way during missions too.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>I-, it's just-</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>I get it. I worry about us too. I'm well aware that war is no place for children, no matter how gifted we are. That's why I look forward to finally defeating our nation's enemies so we can finally be diminished and live normal lives. (smiles)</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>What will happen to us, to me and Kansas, will you remember us?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>Of course big brother. In my dreams, we all share an apartment, pretty similar to this one. I want us to always be in each other's lives. You guys are the good thing I have.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Same here. Which is why I worry about you guys. I don't want you guys to get messed up in the head.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>That's what training is for. There is nothing on the battlefield that we have seen worse in the simulations we've done.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>That's true. But still, look at what it's doing to you guys. Look at what it's doing to me.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Its making us more efficeint soliders. Isn't that the point? The more efficient we are the sooner we can go home. Isn't that what we want? I know you want to leave this place as much as I do.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>That's not what I'm trying to get to. What I'm trying to say is that these simulations, this military base, this war. It's stripping us of our humanity. We are being turned into cold heartless killers. I can't even recognize ourselves on the battlefield. We are like heartless beasts.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Humanity?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Yes, our humanity. Who can you live a normal life, if you lose touch with your humanity?</p></div><p><span class="italic">CHARLOTTE stops washing the dishes for a moment to contemplate her life, she notices that her arms are still reddish despite how many times she washes herself. Bloodstained on her flesh.</span></p><p><span class="italic">KANSAS overhears the conversations.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>What are you going on about big bro? This is just a game, lighten up. Those aren't really people we are killing. They are just NPC's in the simulation.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Puts the dish he is currently wiping dry down</span>)</p><p>Kansas. I'm sorry, but this is not a game.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>You keep saying that, but Father keeps saying otherwise.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Father? Do you mean Doctor Spekstiens?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>Yeah, father.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>That man is not our father.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>What do you mean? He has been raising us since we were young.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>That monster doesn't care about us. Everything we see him, it's in the lab and he is just running tests on us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>He just wants to make sure we are doing okay, he is usually busy with work that all. Daddy is a busy man</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Hmm</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Charlotte, come on, tell me you don't notice what the doctor is up to. He is no father.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Kansas, why do you call the doctor our father?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>That's what he tells me to call him. He doesn't say that to you too?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Not since I was your age... I haven't thought about or called him that in almost a decade. If anything I've always seen big brother as a father figure. He is the one that cares about me and takes me. Not that doctor. He. He is my least favorite thing about this place.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>What are you two going on about?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>That's it. I can't let this keep going on. It's time I tell you guys what's really happening here.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>What do you mean?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>We aren't ever getting out of this place. Not even after the war is over.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>But that's what our superiors keep telling us. Work hard and when the war is over our time will be up and we will be free to go.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>Yeah. Uncles said that when the game is over we can go home and rest.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Those people are not our family. We are their hostages. They kidnapped us. They experimented on us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>Huh?! You're sounding like a crazy old man big bro</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>No, he's not Kansas. Stop for a second. Tell me you don't see the suspicious way the people you call father and uncles have been acting.</p></div><p><span class="italic">KANSAS remains silent.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>I think I remember why I stopped calling them family. Cause they wiped those memories away. I wasn't born here. I remember now. I was taken from my home.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Looks like I triggered a core memory.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>This is not my home...? (<span class="italic">Kansas still to put two and two together. Her world is being shattered</span>)</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>What are we going to do big brother? If they find out we remember, won't they just wipe our minds again</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Not if we break out.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>What about Kansas?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>I'm in.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Did a switch flip in your head? YOure acting different</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>KANSAS</h4><p>I just realized that the NPC's I've been killing are real people and that the family I have is all in my imagination. I want out of this place as soon as possible. I also want a therapist.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p>Me too.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>THOMAS</h4><p>Me three.</p></div><p><span class="italic">They all laugh.</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Coffee Shop Therapy]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/coffee_shop_therapy</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/coffee_shop_therapy</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>SCENE 1</h3><p><span class="italic">RICKY walks into a coffee shop at night. There are bags under his eyes. ISABEL is wiping down the register counter, she also has bags under her eyes. The inside of the coffee shop is decorated with warm white walls with dated posters hung up. The floor is decorated with yellow and brown tiles. ISABEL is dressed in a black and gray uniform with her hair tied up in a knot. RICKY is dressed in a fancy brown trench coat, white gloves, and a nice brown hat.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Walking up to the counter</span>)</p><p>Evening, I'd like a medium caramel latte with almond milk.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL puts the wet rag down and changes her gloves. She begins ringing up RICKY's order on the POS system.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Sure thing! Oh my, you look exhausted, are ya having a rough day?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>You could definitely say that. Speakina which, you don't look so full of energy ya self.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>What gave me away? Was it my drooping eye bags? And that will be $5.99.</p></div><p><span class="italic">RICKY takes his card out of a stuffed wallet and wipes it on the card reader.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">chuckles</span>)</p><p>I guess we're in the same boat.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL watches as the machine prints his receipt and hands it over to him.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>If you don't mind my asking, what has been making you so sleep-deprived?</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL grabs a medium plastic cup from a stack of medium plastic cups and puts it on a counter in her workstation.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>It's family related. Recently I've been put in a position where I have to take on more responsibility than I would like. I was really hoping to become more independent, but it seems like life has other plans. I've spent so many sleepless nights trying to figure out a way out of this but at last, I have nothing.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Wow, we really are in the same boat!</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL takes a measuring cup from a rack on the wall and places it on a grounded espresso dispenser. And pushed the button for medium lattes.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Really? What's been going on with your situation?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>This may surprise you but I don't love my job. I actually wanted to go to school for business but had to give up on that dream when my application was rejected from every school I applied to. Since I had nothing going for me I gave up and accepted my parents' offer to take over the family business.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Your parents own this coffee shop?! I've been coming here for years and didn't realize they had a daughter!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Yeah, I don't blame you. I rarely came to my parents' business in broad daylight. Growing up I didn't want the bullies to find out my parents work in customer service. They would never let me hear the end of it. This line of work is embarrassing, I wanted to escape it but here I am, 20 and destined to work food service while others my age and laying the foundations for their high-paying careers.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL puts the dispensed espresso into the coffee maker and puts the medium plastic up underneath it, and presses the button for medium lattes.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>I don't get it. How is this line of work embarrassing at your age?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>It's cool when you finally turn 16 and first enter the workforce. Most teens start off in this industry. Learning responsibility and work skills. But after a certain point, you have to know to move on to bigger better things. My parents never did. They settled for this, though they had the potential for much better. They settled for this, a job any high schooler can do.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Ma'am with all due respect, I think this line of work is good and honorable. It's challenging just like any other high-collar profession. You don't realize how good you have it. I'd switch places with you in a heartbeat. You have a family with a praise-worthy reputation and business.</p></div><p><span class="italic">Ricky looks pensively to the side, regret colors his face.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>Really? Cause I'd love to take your place. Judging by your appearance, you look like you come from money. You look free.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>An abundance of money isn't always a good thing. Especially when it comes from questionable means. Money isn't everything, serving others is. I think it's so rewarding seeing the smiles your work puts on others' faces. I wish my pops felt the same. All he does is order people around all day to handle the dirty work for him.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>But he earned that though right? When you work hard and reach manager/supervisor status you deserve to rest. You reach such a high place of influence that your word alone accomplishes more than the work of your hands. I want that for myself. I wanted to be the CEO of a large company, not the sole owner and worker of a small coffee shop in some run-down town.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Did my pops earn it? He did. He started at the very bottom of the ladder and worked his way out to the very top. There wasn't a thing that he wouldn't do to reach the top. Growing up I wonder if he even had a conscience with all the things he would do to gain status and power. Now he's old and falling apart and wants to hand over the family business to me, his only son. But I don't want it. I want a simple life. I don't want to walk in his shadow any longer than I already have.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>A wealthy man who wants to leave financial security for a modest life. Now that's something you don't hear every day.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>You're starting to sound like my old man now.</p></div><p><span class="italic">RICKY and ISABEL share a laugh.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY CONT.</h4><p>But I get the feeling of not wanting to work in your parents' shadow. Last week my parents retired and gave the keys to the business to me. And they made sure to make a big deal about me taking over by throwing a huge party earlier. So many people now know I'm the daughter of the most hard-working loving people in the whole neighborhood. It's a little overwhelming if I'm honest. Growing up I felt pressure to live up to them behind closed doors; Now that I'm the face of the business, my failures will be broadcasted to an audience bigger than just my parents.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL grabs a clean metal jug and pours the almond milk she grabbed from the milk into the jug. She heads to the milk steamer and presses the button to auto-clean the machine. She then begins to stream the milk.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Mmm With all that going on in my mind I can see why you don't look too happy to be the new owner of the shop. With all due respect I think you're in a better position than your perspective is allowing you to see. Your parents are kind and honoring folks. You should be proud that that is the legacy that's been laid before you. The business you get to take over has a legacy of bringing smiles, memories, and the much-needed fuel to work the morning shifts for years! Be proud of that.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>I mean I guess you make a good point. My parents have worked hard to make things more positive in this dumpster of a neighborhood. But I don't want to live in the shadow of their legacy. I'm not them, I'm not as skilled and optimistic, and social as they are. I only reluctantly agreed since I don't have anything else going for me. I figured this is better than nothing as I still need money to live off of.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>You don't have anything going for you? What do you mean by that?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Look around you, I'm not sure if you noticed but this shop isn't exactly in the best part of town. Money is hard to come by. And money is the only thing that can make you free.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>You're not entirely correct. In my life, I've seen the love of money create slaves out of free men.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Well, I'm not talking about being obsessed with money, just having enough to not be so chained down by society. In this country, if you want to be successful you have to go to university. I wanted to go. I wanted to get out of this dump.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>I don't blame you. This used to be a nice neighborhood before all the crime moved in. Growing up here must've been rough on you. I'm so sorry, truly I am.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>You don't have to apologize, you had no role to play in all this (chuckles).</p></div><p><span class="italic">A remorseful expression colors RICKY's face, he opens his mouth to speak but hesitate</span>s</p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Besides, I've tried to escape this but life had other plans. I guess I'm stuck in this pitiful coffee shop for the rest of my life.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL takes the steamed milk and pours it into the plastic cup which currently contains liquid espresso.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Surely there are things you enjoy about the work you do? Can the bad things really outweigh the good?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>I mean, for the most part, the work is simple and easy. It is pretty fast-paced, but that fits my personality as I'm always in a rush to get things done. I do enjoy getting to show off my multitasking skills. For example, here's your coffee.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL puts a lid on the latte and hands it to RICKY.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Impressive, (<span class="italic">chuckles and receives the cup of coffee from her hands, he proceeds to take the lid off to let the heat out. He then breathes in the aroma of the latte</span>). Wow, for someone who doesn't like her job, you sure are good at it!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>If you want to keep chatting, maybe we could take a seat at one of the booths? It's closing time so it won't be busy.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles</span>)</p><p>I'd love to.</p></div><p><span class="italic">ISABEL moves from behind the counter, taking with her a medium coffee thermos.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY CONT.</h4><p>I notice you have a drink also. What are you having?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>It's an oat milk latte with caramel drizzle. My mother used to make this for me all the time when I was feeling down.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles</span>)</p><p>Mothers truly have a gift when it comes to cheering up their children. My mother used to make my spaghetti with walnut sauce after I had had a rough day. It always brought joy to my heart.</p></div><p><span class="italic">The two sit down at a small booth in the corner of the shop.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>That's so sweet!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Yeah, I loved my mother. She was the only sane one in the family.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Was your father a crazy man growing up?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Crazy, no. A workaholic, yes. He doesn't know what rest is. My pops only has one mode and that was work. No one is perfect, we sure are all messes aren't we? Well, my pops never sees things like that though. That's what made growing up so frustrating. On top of being a workaholic, my pops is a perfectionist. If he asked you to do something, and you were just a centimeter off from his expectations, he'd really let you have it.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">She covers her mouth in shock</span>)</p><p>Oh my gosh, I'm so sorry to hear that, You definitely had it much worse than I did.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Was your pops hard on you in any way growing up?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>No actually (<span class="italic">takes a sip of her coffee</span>). He was actually really kind and loving. He never knew when to take a break from work, but that was because he was just trying his hardest to provide for us.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>He sounds like a nice man.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Cracks a gentle smile</span>)</p><p>He is. He gives everything his best and people really love him for it.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles and takes a sip of his coffee</span>)</p><p>That's definitely true. There's a reason why I've been coming to Mr. Flamingo's Italian Coffee shop since I was a preteen.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Sighs and fiddles with her thermos</span>)</p><p>It's not fair, my parents are literally perfect. Everyone loves them. They can't seem to do anything wrong. Meanwhile, I can't seem to do anything. Today I got 6 orders wrong and had 10 mental breakdowns. I don't want to live in my parents' shadow.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>I can relate to you. I feel the same way.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Really? Do you feel like a total screw-up too?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles and chuckles</span>)</p><p>The biggest screw-up of all time! I'm my pops' firstborn child. Sometimes it feels like I was born in his shadow. Growing up it always felt like I had to live up to his reputation and outdo him in every regard. I was always comparing myself to him. I've done some things I regret trying to please him.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>Growing up life wasn't hard when I was younger because nothing was expected of me, but as soon as I turned a teenager friends of my family kept comparing me to my parents when they were young. By my age, my parents had accomplished twice as much as I ever had in school, and in sports, heck they were middle school sweethearts. They've never wronged me in any way but sometimes it feels like they set the bar so high. I've become so jaded trying to please everyone and meet the expectations set for me.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>It's frustrating being compared to others. It feels like bondage.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>You can say that again, but what exactly can you do about it? You can't exactly change how people think easily.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Fair, but why care what others think? I've done things I regret for the sake of pleasing people. I've missed out on the opportunity to be doing what I want and love up until now. I'm not going to be a coward. I'm not going to let people put me in a box.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>But if you deviate from your father's legacy aren't you afraid of others seeing you as a disappointing version of my parents? That's how I feel about myself. I need to be like them. What choice do I have?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Stop doing that, being hard on yourself. I see too much of myself in you. I'm the same way. You have a choice, don't care what they think. Don't try to please others. Embrace the cards that life gave you and play them to your advantage! That's what I'm going to do.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>You are making too much sense right now. I guess you're right. I do have a pretty good hand. Maybe I can put my own spin on this coffee shop and make it even more successful. Maybe I can even use some of the things I learned in high school microeconomics to increase our scale of operations!</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles</span>)</p><p>Now that's the right attitude.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>You sure got pretty heated there for a bit. What does your father do? Why was he so hard on you? I noticed you've been pretty vague about what your family does for a living.<br /><span class="italic">RICKY looks to the side pensively and fiddles with his cup. He takes a look at his cup and takes a deep breath. Then he looks back up at ISABEL.</span></p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>It is best if you don't know my pop's line of work in detail. It's less than honorable, and you don't want to get caught up in it. I've done some things I regret trying to live up to his expectations of me. And I'm done. I was on the fence today, but talking to know has given me the push I need to free myself from my pops business.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Slightly shaken, but collects herself</span>)</p><p>You know what, I get it. Whatever you've done I know that's not you. That was you trying to be like your father, you're not your father. You actually have a conscience and feel remorse. And because of that you're already ten times the man he is and your legacy will be an honorable one.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Thank you, I really appreciate that.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>You know we've been talking for a while and I never caught your name.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles</span>)</p><p>My names Ricky. Ricardo Miguel Sanchez.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Smiles back</span>)</p><p>I'm Isabel. Isabella Katalina Flamingo.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With a smug expression</span>)</p><p>Yeah I knew that already, I saw your name-tag.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Looks at her name tag and chuckles</span>)</p><p>Don't you wish everybody always wore a name-tag?</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">Chuckles</span>)</p><p>That would make life easy. Life wouldn't be fun if it were easy.</p></div><p><span class="italic">RICKY's phone rings, he checks it and realizes it is father calling. He takes a deep breath, silences his phone, and begins to get up.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>Well it's getting late, I need to go take care of business back home, next time you see me I'll be a new man with no regrets. Thank you, you helped me realize some changes I need to make.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>ISABEL</h4><p>The feelings are mutual. We should get a coffee again next time you come. Next time you see me you won't recognize me or what I've done with the place.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RICKY</h4><p>(<span class="italic">Smiles</span>) I'd like that. I'll be looking forward to both.</p></div><p><span class="italic">The two smile and hug. RICKY walks out of the shop and the curtains close.</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[humility - a collection of poems]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/collections/humility</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/collections/humility</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="my-experience-writing-revisioning-and-what-was-frustrating">My Experience: Writing, Revisioning, and what was Frustrating</h1><p>I found writing these poems to be creatively and emotionally draining. I kept going back and forth between loving the work I wrote down to absolutely hating it. I knew that I wanted the overall theme of this collection to be humility, and the original drafts definitely stuck along with that goal. But as I kept coming back to each poem and reading it over I would notice its imperfections in clear detail. Seeing each imperfection would upset me and lead me to try to fix it. I often made things worse and deviated from my original purpose.</p><p>Writing poetry started to feel very some to falling into superficial love with someone. In the beginning, youre infatuated with them and they can do no wrong in your eyes. But as you get to know them and see them for who they really are you realize that you cant stand the sight of them. I know it&#39;s harsh! But I really came to hate and be dissatisfied with my work because it was as getting as the image I had in my head!</p><p>I had a hard time leaving room for my reader to think. I wanted them to see things my way. I wanted to get my point across. Learning to hold back from giving the point away was hard. When I read poems myself I hate it when I dont get it, so as a writer, I dont want my reader to feel the same way. As a result, there is always a Tension in my writing between, holding back and giving it all away.</p><h1 id="the-themes">The Themes</h1><p>The main theme of the collection is the benefits of humility. At least that was the goal. My first piece I think really captures it. It starts off by showing how the author is in pain and goes on to reveal that it is his pride that is damaging him. The author because stubborn and stuck in his ways to the point that when failure comes to free him from thinking he is perfect and everyone needs him, he sees it as an interloper. But once he yields, failure humbles him, and humility gives him rest. The second poem was supposed to be about how the author needed to become like a child to accomplish something he couldnt do as an adult.</p><h1 id="favorite-piece">Favorite Piece</h1><p>At the time of this submission, my favorite piece is Reality Check. It used to be Mommy, Daddy, Look! I Can Ride a Bike! But I just feel so dissatisfied with its current state. Reality Check on the other hand has gone through my revisions. It started out as the prompt we worked on in class where we each were tasked with giving a random noun and we all had to write a poem that used each other&#39;s nouns. I wrote a piece about how painful failure feels, but how it is good for us, it keeps us humble. But after last week&#39;s class, I realized it was too preachy towards the end and proceeded to change the ending. I ended up making it look like failure and humility made the author miserable! Which was the opposite of my intent. It&#39;s crazy how changing a few things in a poem can have such a huge impact on the meaning of a poem!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Second Chances]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/second-chances</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/second-chances</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shame and rejection were my only friends,<br>Humiliation was the only clothing I wore around.<br>Once, I slept in the same houses as princes, princesses, and kingsNow I make my bed with the outcasts of society  </p><p>They don&#39;t have much because they aren&#39;t allowed to<br>They have be made to be considered lesser than the elite<br>They are considered to be animals and tools to them<br>And I have been lumped in with them  </p><p>I always felt guilty when I partake in my siblings mockery of the pleasants<br>Our victims knew I was just like them, they saw I was an imposter<br>I can only imagine the hurt of being ridiculed by   someone who looks just like you,<br>Making fun of what makes you you  </p><p>I&#39;ve been trying to make up for my wrongs<br>I&#39;ve been fighting for the forgotten ones of my society<br>The children of the elite love to pull pranks on lower the lower class<br>They know they can get away with it since we have no rights  </p><p>One day I was walking through a quiet street<br>When I heard her cry for help<br>They upper class hoodlums had stolen her bookbag and held her by the neck with fist ready to punch her<br>She recognized me when I came to her aid  </p><p>I was the same one who years earlier I bullied her older sister with my siblings<br>She wasnt afraid of me though<br>Must of heard I had been kicked out of royal family for being just like her<br>Being humbled as helped made me less intimidating  </p><p>I stood up for her<br>Ended up getting myself beat up<br>But she was safe<br>She forgave me for wronging her in the past  </p><p>She accepted me, befriended<br>Clothed me in her kindness and friendship<br>Invited me to live under her roof<br>I am proud to make my bed with the outcasts of society  </p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Soul Mates]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/soul-mates</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/soul-mates</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I usually thought that everyone had a special person made for them,<br>The Eve to their Adam.<br>The matching puzzle piece that completes them,<br>The yin to their yang.  </p><p>I thought life was all about finding that soul mate,<br>There are billions of humans on this planet.<br>The thought of finding my soul mate felt like looking for a needle in a haystack,<br>I became very discouraged.  </p><p>When it comes to love people say you just know when you found the one,<br>Some signal goes off in your heart when your true love is detected.<br>Well, my soul mate radar must be on the fitz,<br>Many times I thought I found true love, and many times they wanted nothing to do with me romantically.</p><p>What is the ideal partner?<br>Is it someone who you have a lot in common with?<br>Is it someone who is your polar opposite?<br>There doesn&#39;t seem to be a common census here.  </p><p>I&#39;ve been looking for love like water in the desert,<br>My heart longs for it in this barren land.<br>That&#39;s when it came to me,<br>I&#39;ve had blindfolds over my eyes this entire time.  </p><p>My soul mate isn&#39;t some manufactured person waiting for me at the end of my search,<br>They are my partner in life, they weren&#39;t created to meet my needs,<br>But through their love, they have come to want to help me.  </p><p>To help me see things in my blind spots,<br>They are the person who I am willing to fight for,<br>The one I&#39;m willing to work things out with,<br>The one I&#39;m willing to lay down my life for.  </p><p>My heart alone didn&#39;t teach me that or show me this,<br>It was only when I mean you that I realize I want to make this work,<br>I will fight against my selfishness because I love you and want to keep loving you.  </p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Caged Bird]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/the_caged_bird</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/the_caged_bird</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>SCENE 1</h3><p><span class="italic">CHARLOTTE walks into her bedroom. Claudia is standing over the shattered pieces of CHARLOTTE's violin. In CLAUDIA's right hand is the snapped neck of Charlotte's violin. There is a guilty expression on CLAUDIA's face.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE</h4><p class="parenthetical">(<span class="italic">With tears forming in her eyes.</span>)</p><p>You devil! You cold-hearted lizard! How could you do such a wicked thing to me? You conniving snake! You waited for no one to be home so that you could attack my violin! You immoral woman, how dare you damage my pride and joy! You didn't expect me to be home so early, did you? You thought you were going to be able to get away with this. I would have accused you anyways. Deep down in my heart, I've always known that you've hated me. I see the way you look at me across the dinner table. I suspected there was great bitterness in your heart. But I didn't want to believe that my own flesh and blood could be capable of such evil.<br />You know how important my violin was to me. You know I had a competition coming up. One that would change my life forever. Day after day I've been practicing for this opportunity. Mother and Father have given me their full support. I thought you did too, but I guess you were lying through your teeth. You knew that the grand prize was a lump-sum of money, enough to radically change someone's life. You know how much I've wanted to move out of these slums and go to the big city. You know how much I've wanted to be free to enjoy the luxuries of life. I should have kept my dreams a secret between me and my Mother.<br />You were always jealous of my dreams. We were both born in the same lowly station in life, but I always dreamed of a life much better than this. From the moment I learned to speak my mind I could sense that bitterness and envy were bubbling up in your rotten heart. You're a no-good complacent hag. Just because your life is going nowhere doesn't give you the right to try to halt mine! To think, my own flesh and blood would be my greatest opposition!<br />Do you hate me because my Mother comes from fortune, and yours was poor? You know that doesn't matter because she gave all that up when she married Father, right? My mother, our mother, loves you like her own, but now that I think of it, you always looked at me and her with contempt.<br />I never went to school. Mother thought she could teach me better than public school teachers. She'd boast that she was taught by the best teachers Germany had to offer. She offered the opportunity to you, but you thought it was beneath you, but now look at me. I speak better than you, I'm more musically talented than you. Heck, you have no sense of pitch when you "singing". I'm well versed in history and politics, math and sciences. I know that there is a life much better than the one I'm currently living in. I refuse to be locked in this cage called poverty forever.<br />You are aware of how hard life has been for me since childhood. I had no friends besidesmy beloved violin. The neighborhood kids were always jealous of me. (In a mockingvoice) Oh, she thinks she is better than us with her proper speech and brain the size ofan encyclopedia. She thinks she is rich, but she is dirt poor like us. She is worse than usbecause she doesn't know her place. She thinks she can cross the chasm between the richand poor, hahaha.<br />(Speaking normally) You know how much I want to spread my wings and get out of this place. You know how I have had such a hard time fitting in. You know how much I hate this place. They ridicule me for being ambitious. You know how much I've been belittled and attacked by those heathens.<br />How dare you fully align yourself with those who seek to make my life miserable. You never had empathy for me. You never stood up for me when the kids bullied me. I forgave you for that. I understand peer pressure is a heck of a drug. I always had your back when Mother and Father asked why you did nothing to help me. You actually had friends and I didn't want you to get in trouble and lose them. So why, why would you be so cruel that you would destroy my only friend?</p></div><p><span class="italic">Looking at her broken violin.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>CHARLOTTE CONT.</h4><p>You were my way out of this pit called poverty, and now you're dead. Your neck crushed like a gazelle's underneath the ferocious teeth of a lioness. Claudia, you heartless heathen, you crushed my joy. I hope life crushes what little remains of your pitiful dreams!<br />Why did this have to be my lot in life? I am cursed with this desire to break free from my station in life. Why was I cursed with poverty? I am a caged bird. Poverty is my cage, and my violin was the key to my cage. Now I am stuck. My only means of joy and freedom is gone.<br />I can't afford to replace you, my dear. My happiness will now be forever locked away on the other side of this cage. Curse you, Claudia. I am now as cold as you are. You always felt embarrassed by me. You always disowned me in public. Now, it's my turn to disown you! I renounce the blood we share. You are not my sister, you're my enemy! I despise you. You are like a bottom-feeding crab in a bucket of crabs. You are too stubborn and jealous to watch another from your station in life succeed.<br />You have hurt me, and you've done it for the last time. I'm running away from home because I can't stand to be in the same building as you. Your bitter heart disgusts me. Your soul is as filthy as a pig's pen. You are dead to me. If it truly is my fate to die poor, I don't want my tomb to be near your cursed soul!</p></div><p><span class="italic">CHARLOTTE finishes picking up the broken pieces of her violin. She holds them in her arms like a wounded pet and leaves the scene in tears. CLAUDIA falls down to her knees and cries.</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Restless Mind]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/restless_mind</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/restless_mind</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes I wonder if you think about me too,<br>You always cross my mind in the quiet of the night.<br>Like a nagging pain in my heart,<br>The uncertainty of your love tears me apart.  </p><p>Do you think about me too?<br>Does your heart ache to hear from me too?<br>Does life prevent you from reaching out like a club bouncer,<br>Halting your attempts to be receptive to my love?  </p><p>Do you think about me too?<br>Am I just a thought in the back of your mind?<br>Am I a faint thought, a distant memory,<br>Another option, just a backup.  </p><p>A friend told me Im hurting myself,<br>Thinking about you thinking of me.<br>Pondering the intentions of your heart,<br>Is like rubbing a prickly cactus.  </p><p>I wont think about you.<br>I wont think about you.<br>I wont think about you!<br>I know you dont think about me too.  </p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Big Break]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/the_big_break</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/the_big_break</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I quickly slid into the knee-long unstained lab coat. I hadnt worn one of these since my freshman year of college when I took general chemistry. One by one I carefully button up the overcoat, making sure to not miss a hole. Taking a deep breath, calming my nerves, I look down at the poor unsuspecting lab intern I had just mugged. He laid on the floor like a heavy bag of rice. He looked dead but his heart was still beating, Im no murderer.</p><p>I began to pick up his scrawny body and gently laid him on the back seat of his sedan like a bed. I started his car and rolled the windows down a smidge, enough to let cool air in so he doesnt suffocate. Im no murderer. I understand that I look rather suspicious right now, but I swear Im the good guy here! My conscience continues to pierce my sensitive heart with its accusation, but I bury them deep into the recesses of my mind and fix my attention on his uncomfortable lab goggles over my fluffy curly hair and out my chiseled face. I pin his nametag over the left-hand side of my chest. Today I, Ben &quot;Benjamin&quot; Jaime Givvins, am about to perform the greatest conspiracy uncovering since John Marks exposed project MK-Ultra!</p><p>What am I about to expose you ask? And why is it so serious that I felt the need to beat up a nerd, steal his clothes, and leave him passed out in his car? If someone gave you a map that led to a treasure of untold riches that would secure you for life wouldnt you take it? I recently graduated from the Rochester Institute of Technology with a degree in photojournalism. I have student loans to pay, and I have no real weight or reputation to my name. My fossil of a boss thinks Im a naive child that doesnt know what he is doing, and my coworkers think Im a silly baby. Despite my numerous awards from my time in university, in the workplace, they are counted as rubbish.</p><p>I need a big story! Something so juicy Ill be able to win their respect as a reporter. Recently I got an anonymous tip from a worker at a local lab detailing the inhuman practices going on there. It was a slow Monday morning, I was sipping my tall caramel cappuccino while scrolling through my email in boredom. I noticed an unusual email address had sent the Newspaper a message begging for help, and yet for some reason, it was marked as spam. I curiously opened it.</p><p>The writer wrote about how he had just been fired from his position. His conscience couldnt contain it anymore, and he spoke out against his workspace. He wrote of how his employer, The Bradster Laboratory 20 minutes away from the city, had been kidnapping children and experimenting on them to create super soldiers for years! When I brought this email weirdly marked for spam to my higher-ups, they laughed in my face.</p><p>I know youre new to this and eager to get your hands dirty uncovering a story thatll make you famous, but you have to realize that not every lead is trustworthy. This is just some disgruntled worker who got fired. He provided no evidence, just baseless claims. Theres a reason why its marked for spam said Jones Goodmen, the head writer for the Paper. I walk about defeated to my desk. I know I know, I need more evidence than an anonymous email before I can make such a lofty accusation of this Laboratory. I was too eager to report on a real story instead of some mundane story on a fire department rescuing a local elderly womans cat. So if it&#39;s evidence they want, it&#39;s evidence they will get. Thats how I ended up here. I know, my motives arent exactly noble. But a lot of good will come out of what Im doing! I can feel it in my gut!</p><p>I slide my small Sony mirrorless camera into the large pocket by my right thigh. On it I have an 18mm-70mm kit lens I own. I figured Id need all the range I can get, I dont exactly know what Im going to be getting myself into here. I made sure to have my camera on silent mode so I didnt blow my cover. I then grab my tiny tape recorder and press record. I slide it into my chest pocket. After a deep breath, I make my way down to the laboratory. I walked with my chest to the sky, if I allowed my body to display anxiety my cover may have been broken.</p><p>I am greeted by a short stubby scientist with bushy gray hair. He had thin circular black glasses over his eyes. He too wore a knee-length lab coat, only his wasnt spotless. Rather it was a tie-dyed mess of various colors from various chemical reactions. His hand was gripping onto a thin wooden clipboard. He extends his boney arm to shake my hand. Our blue latex glove-covered hands lock and sneak as we firmly grip and shake each other&#39;s arms. I take a quick glance at his name tag, which is slightly tilted rightwards. Doctor Malvin Kontigo, Head Scientist.</p><p>Are you ready to begin your first day Timothy Gallen? he says in his old croaky voice. My conscience pinches me again as I look at my nametag, I wince internally and force my head to nod up and down. He walks through dark tinted glass doors and I follow him. The interior of the facility is a plain metallic gray, with blinding led lights illuminating the long lanky hallway. He led me down the corridor and I followed. I slowly reached my hand into my large pocket and grabbed onto my camera. I feel around it until I am certain I have my hand on the grip with my pointer finger hovering over the shutter button.</p><p>Welcome to Bradster Laboratory! he says enthusiastically. I know it doesn&#39;t look like much, but that&#39;s because this is just for show, she says as he gestures to the various doors and offices that populate the corridor. I&#39;m starting to think that my coworkers were right. There&#39;s not much experimentation going on here, they don&#39;t even have a microscope or test tube on site. It&#39;s just a glorified office space. I&#39;m starting to feel a little downcast, I went through a lot of trouble to get here just to be disappointed. Maybe I should be happy that they aren&#39;t conducting illegal experiments on humans and maybe I should be glad they aren&#39;t kidnapping children.</p><p>&quot;This is what we want to show the media when they come to investigate supposed &#39;illegal activities&#39;, can you believe the accusations they make against it.&quot; I&#39;m starting to feel a little ashamed of myself. &quot;Well, they are right!&quot; He says smugly. My eyes beam up as he says it. &quot;The Governments of the world are having another historical arms race. Only this time it is a race to see who will develop the strongest super soldiers the fastest. Here at Bradster Labs, we were using somewhat unconventional methods to produce truly high results. We reach the end of the corridor and start pushing buttons on what appears to be a thermostat. You might want to get a little closer to me buddy, he says with his eyebrows raised a smidge. As I step onto the same tile as he, the ground we are standing on begins to sink into the ground. Welcome to the real Bradster Labs! He gestures to the various labs and rooms.</p><p>Here at Bradster Labs, we are highly inspired by the biological marvels of mother nature. Mother Nature has produced creatures of incredible strength and feats. Take for example the panther. He leads me to a glass panel cell. On the other side of the panel is a muscular, fair skin man. His biceps were bigger than his head, and he was covered in silver spots on his arms. Capable of running up to 50 mph, leaping up to 18 feet off the ground, and capable of great feats of strength. Imagine having a soldier capable of those very things. The enemy troops wouldn&#39;t know what hit them. This subject we are currently beholding is the pinnacle of Bradster Laboratory Biological Engineering! The man on the other side began to growl. His pointy ears twitched, and he turned around and looked at us. His teeth were sharper than the average person, and he had a furrial look in his eyes. This is Commander Panther, we have been engineering him since he was a young orphan. He has the same capabilities as Mother Natures panther. He is a killing machine says Doctor Kontigo with pride. Now follow me this way, Ill show you your first assignment The doctor walks away and heads back into the main hallway. I quickly grab my camera and snap a picture of the beast of a man. He snaps and leaps onto the panel. I jump a bit back and give a little high-pitched shriek. I hide my camera and run after the Doctor.</p><p>He leads me to another room. This room is a huge indoor track. The ceiling resembles a bright morning sky and a gentle breeze runs throughout the room keeping it cool. This is our current project, Subject C, C for cheetahs. Imagine having a soldier who could outrun a vehicle, and had enough stamina to last for days. As he speaks I notice a yellow blur running circles around the large football size track. &quot;I know you&#39;re new here but I am placing Subject C in your hands. She will do exactly as you say. The Subjects here know there are drastic disciplinary actions for disobedience. Escort her back to her cell, she knows the way back. In a few minutes or so someone will pick you up and escort you to the dining hall.&quot; I nod. I&#39;m a little nervous to be alone with her after seeing how the last subject wanted to eat my head. But I&#39;m not going to lose my clue, I&#39;m not going to blow my cover. I turn my attention back to the blur on the track. I can hear it screaming with shouts of joy.</p><p>Subject C is very fast, I can barely keep track of them I finally mutter.</p><p>Yes, she is! She too is a biological engineering marvel here at Bradster Labs! A super soldier capable of running at speeds up to 70mph, jumping up to 35 feet far and 15 feet high, and has heightened senses. Take good care of her, I have to go attend to some business he then summons Subject C and leaves the room.</p><p>In a blink of an eye, I am hit with a rush of wind. I wince again. The gush takes me back and bit and I shield my eyes from the debris. As I place my hands down I am standing face to face with a woman about 53. She is clothed head to top in a skin-tight reflective metallic jumper that was covered in black spots. She had a metallic tail that seemed to have a mind of its own and a narrow helmet with wide goggle-like eyes, a small pink cat nose, and pointy ears protruding from the sides of the cheetah-like helmet. She pushes a button on the back of her helmet and you can see air leak out. She then proceeds to take the helmet completely off, and I am about to see her face. She has dark caramel skin and dirty blonde hair that stops gently at her shoulders. She had similar markings as Commander Panther on her forehead. She looks significantly less intimidating than him despite having the same pointy ears and teeth. She looks sad that her fun is over. &quot;Subject C right? That&#39;s what the doctor calls you. Do you happen to have a real name?&quot; I ask her with an inviting smile.</p><p>&quot;A real name? Not that I know of. No one has ever cared to give me one. Why do you ask this?&quot; Her eyes start to come to life as if she has been dumped in ice-cold water. She tilts her head from side to side and I can tell she is examining me. These people never thought to give her a name. Makes sense, is it easier to perform cruel acts on a person if they are just an object to you? This is not right.</p><p>&quot;Because you are a person, and people have names. Mind if I can you Charlotte?&quot; She starts looking flushed as I ask her. </p><p>&quot;SS-Sure.&quot; She manages to say. I can tell by the look in her eyes that this is the first time she&#39;s been seen and treated as someone more than a test subject. </p><p>You dont act like the other scientists, whats up with you? She asks suspiciously. I looked around to make sure the other scientists werent around.</p><p>My name is Benjamin Givvins and I am a Reporter. I got a tip that this place was performing illegal experiments on people and I came to investigate and blow the lid off this place.&quot;</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Make the Greatest Animated Movie Ever]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/essays/how-to-train-your-dragon</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/essays/how-to-train-your-dragon</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="how-to-make-the-greatest-animated-movie-ever">How to Make the Greatest Animated Movie Ever</h1><h1 id="the-summary">The Summary</h1><p>When it comes to producing emotionally engaging character-driven animated movies, Disneys Pixar has the crown. They have consistently cunned out great films over the years, however, in my eyes, none of their films rivals the story told in Dreamworks 2010 hit How to Train a Dragon. How to Train you Dragon is a coming of age tale of an outcast Viking teen named Hiccup who struggles to find acceptance from his father and his village. He doesnt match the description of your typical Viking build: biceps the size of boulders, shoulders as broad as mountains, and a face as hairy as a Wolly Mammoth. He is as thin as a toothpick with arms even thinner. Looking at him you feel more sorry for him than you do intimidate by him. He is from the village Berek, which has a huge pest problem, rampant village fire-breathing dragons terrorize the inhabitants nonstop! Killing a dragon is a right of passage on this island. But when faced with the opportunity of a lifetime to kill a dragon and win the praise and approval of his father and village, Hiccup cant do it. He sees himself in the dragon, misunderstood. He then goes on to get to know and befriend the member of the species that his village hates and would kill on site. Hiccups story is a beautiful one told with the aid of an amazing score and impressive visuals.</p><h1 id="the-music-and-visuals">The Music and Visuals</h1><p>This movie excels in its use of music! The score is so perfectly in-sync with the movie you cant tell which was produced first the soundtrack of the scenes. The score does such a great job of making you forget about the real world. As it&#39;s playing you are in Berk. You are a Viking villager tagging along with Hiccup and the main cast. The music holds the hands of your heart and leads you through the emotions of the cast. You feel the threat of the dragons in the opening scene as the music grabs a hold of you and shakes you frantically. You feel the eerieness and spookiness and Hiccup approaches the almost mythical Nightfury, that no one had lived to tell the tale of. You feel the young love budding as Hiccup takes his peer Astrid on a scenic flight through the clouds at sunset. The score works in tandem with the stunning visuals. The scene that gets me every time is the Romantic Flight. It is a short scene runtime-wise, but in-universe spans a few hours. The scene starts shortly after Astrid, Hiccups rival and crush earn the respect of Toothless, the Nightfury that Hiccup befriends. Toothless takes to two on a romantic trip through the clouds during sunlight. The clouds are an inviting pink hue. And the awe of Astrid&#39;s face sells the realism of the whole scene. She is the viewer! She is feeling what she is feeling! This film gets us into the heads of the characters in a way only a book written in the third person could!</p><h1 id="the-father-son-dynamic">The Father-Son Dynamic</h1><p>By far the greatest aspect of the movie, the characteristic that makes it soar above its peers, is its Father-Son Narrative. Hiccup and his father Stoic are stark opposites. Hiccup is an oxymoron for a Viking, whilst Stoic is the dictionary definition of a village. Throughout the movie, these two are contrasted with each other. Hiccup is the Village laughing stock and his father is the revered chief. Hiccup is unsure of himself, throughout the whole movie he is trying to fit in with a people and culture that is contrary to his personality. Stoic on the other hand has always known who it was, what he was capable of, and has been unapologetic about it his whole life. Stoic would never second-guess killing a dragon. He grew up seeing them as devils that enjoyed burning down his village and stealing his people&#39;s cattle more than anything else. Dragons werent redeemable to him, they were heartless animals.</p><p>Hiccup is raised the same way, tries to subscribe to his familys ideals, but finds he relates so much to these terrifying beasts. He sees another side to them, and a gentler side that his people never saw. This puts him in even greater opposition to his father. Stoic was always disappointed in Hiccup. Hiccup was not the son he always wanted. Hiccup knew this to be true and that&#39;s why he tried so hard to impress Stoic to no avail. Hiccup and Stoic seem to have nothing in common, and can never see eye to eye. They are never listening to each other and are both never on the same page when they talk to each other. Things change when Stoic prideful bites more than he can chew when he ignores Hiccup&#39;s warnings and takes an arm to take down the dragon queen and its nest. He grounds Hiccup and enslaves Toothless and takes him with him. Things quickly go south for Stoic but Hiccup and his friends find their way to the island on the backs of newly trained dragons to rescue Stoic and the villagers.</p><p>One of the characters notes that Hiccup is just as stubborn as Stoic. Stoic was humbled by his failure of foolishly putting his people at risk against his sons judgment and realized that the so-called devils he was afraid of could be tamed and loved and love themselves. When Hiccup and Toothless and knocked underwater by the Queen Dragon, Stoic doesnt hesitate to rescue them both! The son he had disowned became his dearly beloved son. His sons best friend, the dragon, the best he hated, became the pet he respected. We see Stoic apologize for the way he treated Hiccup. We see him accept Hiccup for who he was instead of trying to make him something he is not. Both these characters&#39; journeys to finally understand each other made this movie such a captivating watch!</p><h1 id="my-first-impression">My First Impression</h1><p>Growing up it was rare that I would get a chance to watch movies. My family never really went to the movie theatres. I come from an immigrant household and during my youth money for entertainment was hard to come by. If the movie wasnt on tv or wasnt being streamed in the classroom, I wasnt ever going to get a catch to see it. As I got older and more desperate to watch these films I figured out ways to watch them without waiting for them to be on tv or lucky enough for a teacher to bless us with a film for a treat. Being a smart and resourceful 5th grader I discovered that the local library actually allowed you to rent out movie discs! So I rented a copy and watched the film in my parent&#39;s bedroom as it was the only room in the house with a DVD player that I could operate. This movie blew your small fragile mind into a thousand pieces! I was captured by the characters, the scenery, the locations, and the soundtrack. Ive had a good relationship with my father all my life. We never fight, I do as he says. I make him proud. And yet, despite my fairly positive childhood, I was able to emphasize Hiccup. The movie did such a great job helping me understand a dynamic that was alien to my own life. What initially drew me into the world of How to Train Your Dragon was the colorful and uniquely crafted dragons, but what kept in engaged in the movie was everything else! This movie will go down in my mind as one of the greatest movies ever made. They had interesting characters. It was a simple story at its core, with everything else acting like icing on the cake!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intro to Galanthus]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/collections/intro-to-galanthus</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/collections/intro-to-galanthus</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-big-idea-of-this-poetry-collection">The Big Idea of this Poetry Collection</h1><p>For this Poetry Collection, I wanted to write poems that took place within a fictional universe that I have been writing about for the past few years. In this class I have come to see and appreciate poetry as a great medium to write and tell stories. Poetry as a medium has tools that help it cover emotions and thoughts in a manner superior to novels. In my mind, poetry offers a snapshot into a character&#39;s mind. It allows the writer to focus on what they are feeling and really draw it out. So that&#39;s what I decided to do.</p><p>I tried to write the poems in such a way that didn&#39;t require any background information. These poems exist in an alternate version of our very own solar system. A place where the planets are ruled by an egotistical conquering prideful alien race known as the plenatites, due to their planet-like strength and abilities. They have a rigid hierarchy based on power. Because power is so important to the plenatite race, they favor stronger members and brush off the weaker ones and treat them as nuisances. They don&#39;t allow the lowest grade to interact with the high ones as they see them as a waste of time. The lower you go down the Plenatite Hierarchy the weaker the plenatites are.</p><p>The main character in these poems is based on the planet Pluto. As you know Pluto is no longer considered a planet like Earth or Jupiter. Because of its size and other factors, it is considered a dwarf planet. The main character is a low-class plenatite, who was born into a family of ruling plenatites, where he did not fit in with his royal siblings. Pluto is banished to the outskirts of the Milky Way Sector for resembling the lower members of society.</p><p>These poems are all from Pluto&#39;s perspective as he comes to terms with being looked down upon and rejected by his family. The second poem deals with how he comes to terms with his hypocrisy in the past and later finds redemption and a friend. And the last poem is very different from the previous two. It deals with the idea of soul mates in a very general manner. It is very detached from the world that the previous poems inhabit. I did that on purpose. Even though they are the main character&#39;s thoughts, they are also my own and I want to make that statement able to stand on its own. The main character comes up with these thoughts a little bit after the events of the previous poem and they are a stark contrast to his siblings&#39; view of love as mentioned in the first poem.</p><h1 id="my-experience-writing-revisioning-and-what-was-frustrating">My Experience: Writing, Revisioning, and what was Frustrating</h1><p>I knew I wanted to write three poems that told a small part of a story I have always wanted to write at the very beginning. So when it came down to writing these poems I just kept my premise in mind, and allowed the story to play in my mind, and carefully documented the characters&#39; thoughts and emotions like an all-knowing observer who was close to the characters. The most frustrating part about this is trying to fully and accurately convey the ideas that were playing in my head.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mommy, Daddy Look! I Can Ride a Bike]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/bike</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/bike</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bike riding is a child&#39;s rite of passage<br>Gather up all your grown-up friends, I&#39;m sure they can ride a bike<br>They know what its like to feel the wind on their skin like a kite,<br>Being free and light, nimble like water as they swerve around obstacles  </p><p>I am an outliner<br>I am full of embarrassment and regret<br>I am chained on the ground<br>Bounded by the fear of falling  </p><p>You see he that keeps me imprison<br>He has kept me from learning to ride a bike<br>Each time I try is like trying not to fall off a tightrope  </p><p>Doubt and Anxiety remind me again that I&#39;m going to fail<br>So give in I might as well<br>My friend had empathy for me, she showed me a simpler way  </p><p>&quot;If you&#39;re not ready to run, then waddle like a toddler<br>Paddle your feet along the ground and try to steer<br>This will help you improve your balance dear&quot; </p><p>Slowly and steadily I had no more fears<br>As my confidence increased I stretched myself to higher levels<br>Like a child finally figuring out how to walk and run about<br>The muscle memory became ingrained and the skill was now simple and plain<br>After all that trial and error, it clicked it was there<br>I&#39;m free now fear! I can pedal anywhere  </p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reality Check]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/reality-check</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/reality-check</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am in the wilderness<br>My will and happiness drying up<br>A worm languishing in the hot arid sun<br>My strength depleting, and I&#39;m all alone  </p><p>I am on fire,<br>A star in the night sky<br>Radiant, glistening, sustaining men with my greatness<br>I can do no wrong  </p><p>But like an interloper in the dark<br>He has come to plunder my radiance and expose my weakness<br>He has come to knock me out of the sky<br>To save me from myself  </p><p>I was drunk on my own greatness when he came to my aid<br>A loving father to remind me, I am not like them<br>The stars, radiant and glistening, bright without imperfection<br>Who am I but weak and dependent, a babe in need of rest  </p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rejection]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/rejection</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/rejection</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I always felt like I didn&#39;t fit in,<br>This became all more clear when my brothers finally had their way.  </p><p>My people have a rigid class system,<br>If you resemble the bottom of the totem you&#39;re treated like dirt.<br>My brothers walked all over me growing up,<br>They were royalty and I was a peasant lucky to share the same air they breathed.  </p><p>Father continued to shine forth his love for me,<br>But all I felt was the cold mocks from my siblings.  </p><p>They poked fun at my height, my frailties, and my shortcomings,<br>They could move boulders by the will of their minds,<br>And I was lucky if I could nudge a pebble.<br>They had tens of wives and 100 hundreds of children.<br>I just had no one to call my own.  </p><p>But Father continued to shine forth his love for me,<br>Yet all I felt was the cold mocks from my siblings.  </p><p>Our Father has the highest authority among our people,<br>He was a great conqueror and a fierce lover.<br>He had a great love for his children,<br>He gave each of them their own planet to rule when they became of age.</p><p>And I looked forward to the day I&#39;d reach that age,<br>The day the family&#39;s ugly duckling would become a swan,<br>But my brothers had their way.  </p><p>I always felt I didn&#39;t fit in,<br>And they made that feeling a reality.<br>They used their influence to cause an uproar amongst our people at the thought of me,<br>Little ol me becoming a ruler.  </p><p>They convinced my father&#39;s advisors that I was a mistake and didn&#39;t belong,<br>And when my father retired and handed over power to my brothers,<br>They cast me out of my own home.<br>No longer could I feel my father&#39;s love,<br>Just resentment for my siblings.  </p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Don't They Get Me]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/why_dont_they_get_me</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/why_dont_they_get_me</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>INT. MIDORI'S LIVING ROOM - EVENING.</h3><p><span class="italic">RONNE MIDORI enters the living room.</span></p><div class="dialogue"><h4>NARRATOR</h4><p>Ronne Midori is an Afro-Asian American male who's about fifth-teen. He has a medium build with short kinky curly hair. He is a sharp kid and is rather reserved. He is not normal and doesn't know how to deal with it, so he keeps it bottled up inside. He is a defect, he's not like normal people. He's like those monsters he sees on the channel five news. He just came back home after a rough day at school, he overheard people talking down on defects and was infuriated by it.</p></div><div class="dialogue"><h4>RONNE MIDORI</h4><p>WHY! (<span class="italic">Slams Door</span>). I don't understand why they hate us some much. Don't they see the hypocrisy? What happened to loving one another. It seems like that whole concept goes out the door when its someone you don't get. Why are were so frighten? So, what we could tear down a city whenever we want, WE DON'T! Okay I know that sounds wild, but you could say the same with the government. If they wanted to, they could whip out an ENTIRE city if they wanted. Besides defects are in the minority. We're peaceful, well at least everyone I've met have been. Why must humanity always have an enemy? They've started a propaganda war once again about something they don't understand. Somehow, they've spun humans that have developed extraordinary abilities into heartless monsters. <br />(<span class="italic">Sighs</span>) Why? Why are we monsters? (Ronne looks at his hands and precedes to roll his sleeves up). You know sometimes I wonder if I would still feel as strongly as I do about defects if I wasn't one of them. (Ronne gets a gentle smirk and watches as heat protrudes from his arms). Maybe I'd be scared too. I'd be scared if I was powerless in a world filled with people like me. But that isn't what I'm living in. There very few of us out there. I have a strong feeling there's whole families out there like this, defected, scared to be ridiculed and turned on. I hate it. I hate this. I hate how humans are so quick to turn on their neighbors. <br />It's funny you know (<span class="italic">Ronne simmers the flame on his arms and rolls down his sleeves</span>), this whole defect manhunt in the news is pretty ironic. It wasn't that long ago where they were making movies about super-powered beings and writing stories about them. They made them so sympathetic and yet they still managed to seem greater than life. People used to adore superheroes. So, why then do they arbor us defects? I don't get it, we're like the stories written down for centuries come to life. No, we're not like those stories, we ARE those stories. It's time we stop hiding and being vocal. We can't get change just complaining and weeping in the shadows. I tried of listening to my classmate talk ill of defects knowing they know little about their struggle. Well, even though I want to do something about this I can't do it looking like this, I need a costume. Just in case this all backfires and they form a mob pit and chase me out of town like I'm Frankenstein (<span class="italic">Ronne chuckles</span>).</p></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sip]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/sip</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/sip</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I hate the aroma of coffee it reminds me of her<br>Her beautiful scent did not match her personality<br>My coffee is cold, just like my soul, I miss her so</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's All We Got]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/its-all-we-got</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/its-all-we-got</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I stared across the barren diner table. My husband and I had just arrived, it was our first date in decades ever since the kids came into the picture. My husband was only in his late thirties but he looked twice that. We arent super wealthy, heck we came barely make the rent payments on time. We both came from bad neighborhoods when were young. Everyone around us was either poor or homeless or just void of spirit and happiness. The problems of life and money sucked all the joy out of life. Its hard to enjoy yourself when the threat of an eviction note is constantly looming over your head. </p><p>And yet still the people kept perceiving through the hardships. And even though I didnt understand it when I was young and naive, still a sponge absorbing the world around me, it all clicked when I meet Jonathan. Love. The best weapon against sadness and despair. The only thing that can fuel your journey in life after being drained from your daily nine to five and sucker punched by your boss and constrained with bills. </p><p>Never has Eltons song meant so much, I used to hear it on the radio as a child. It always just sounded catchy, I never understood the meaning of hope it was trying to convey. I looked at my husband&#39;s beautiful dirty brown eyes. Dirty like the back-killing labor he does at his construction job, but that&#39;s the dirtiness I love. He looks at my messy brown hair, plagued with frizzes and split ends. He didnt even care I was looking like a slob, he always overlooked my imperfections. We smiled at each other for what felt like an eternity. The waitress came up to our table and brought us back to reality.</p><p>Lovely evening am I right, she said as she smiled at us, May I take Y&#39;all order.</p><p>My husband replied, Yes, my wife and I would like</p><p>I dont even remember what we ate, I just know I loved it, Haha.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Jittery Fax Machine]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/jittery-fax-machine</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/jittery-fax-machine</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Uhm, I say as my mind buffers and loads its next response. Hi, Bethany. Whats wrong? I allow the words to fall out mouth gentle like helicopter seeds. I tried to be straightforward hoping said get to a straightforward answer, but instead of a one sentence response, I got a novel. Guess this is how it feels when teachers want a one-page essay and get a packet.</p><p>So, the other day I was sitting in class when announcements came on, she began, setting up her story. You know the youzhes, the pledge, followed by silence and a news flash. Well, they were talking about the Football game and h-how, ya know its this Saturday... The words seemed to jam as the tried to leave her mouth. She was acting like a broken fax machine, red, overheating and producing some strange robotic noises. I kind of felt the need to just interrupt her before she exploded.</p><p>Do you want to go to the game with me? I might take hours get a knock joke, or miss all the potential signs that a girl like me, but I know when an acquaintance wants to hang out. She malfunctions; drops her luggage onto the floor and erupts into bright giggles. Glad to see she was happy, but I needed her to finish quickly. I was already running late to class and my girlfriend was waiting for me in the library.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Street Lights]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/streetlights</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/streetlights</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I slumped down a dozen flights of steps. In my right hand, my leather brown suitcase clenched onto its life. It was quite heavy today, consuming all the tasks I was handed. You shouldve seen the mountain of documents in my tiny office. Every day Id burn through all that paper; my work ethic was unmatched. Now it seems like my fire is flickering out. I make simple blunders, despite the fact Ive become more robotic.</p><p>Why though? I wonder as I watch the busy vehicles race by, leaving red streaks behind them. Something must be distracting me. The pay at the office is adequate. Ive bought nice trendy clothes, along with a plethora of fancy pens and watches that take up my entire living room-sized closet. With the multitude of raises Ive received, Ive also purchased bought my own Mercedes Benz. Yet it feels like I have nothing meaningful. Why is there still a hole in my soul? I think to myself as I slide into my yellow cab. Ive wasted my life, my conscious whispers to me as I stare out the rusty cab windows, staring at the streetlights. Maybe hes right, even after all the work Ive done, the strings Ive pulled, the facade Ive lived, I am still not even rich. Sure, Im upper middle class, but it&#39;s as if the last 30 years have been for nothing.</p><p>My Benz was recently stolen, and my elegant, humble abode in the gated neighborhood in the hills was sacked. They stole everything Id worked so hard to earn, leaving my house in a barren state.</p><p>OH, MY GOD! Are you alright, I heard what happened to your house THEY DID WHAT?!... Dang, whoever did this is scum, nothing but a bunch of scavengers!... If theres anything I can do, tell me and Ill be there, said my sister. Although she wasnt actually there. I imagined it like I always do. Ive played out that extract phone call for 2 years now. Yeah, my house was broken into 2 years ago, everyone knows. They just dont care. Neither do I, Ive still been working hard, but instead of buying replacements to my stolen belongings, I buy nothing but bottles. </p><p>The ride home sure is long. I sigh in emotional agony and watch as my warm breath condensates on the cab window. It was my favorite thing about winter when I was young; my sister and I would do this on every car ride to my aunt&#39;s house for Christmas. Action packed sibling duo films would play out on those windows. Sadly, there hasnt been a sequel in decades. We havent talked in decades, nor seen or been with each other. We got along well back in the day, but nowadays I only get along with myself. Only I understand me.</p><p>I feel like an orphan surrounded by my foster family most days. The streetlights that would normally tower and frighten kids at night comfort me. They understand me, and I can relate to them. I too wake up to go to my job, work all day, and go back to sleep. We dont need leisure time; it is a distraction, right? </p><p>Still, I wonder whether I made the right choices sometimes on the cab rides. As we drive, I see my brothers, the streetlights, shine on happy children jumping about swinging back and forth in the secure hands of loving mothers. They look so happy while the lights, on the other hand, appear gloomy and miserable. Lately, I feel even more like a street light. Life gets mundane, I think to myself every ride home from work. Questions why my life turned out like this swim to the surface, pushing out orders from my boss and reminders of taxes to file. I repeat the mantra that helped me cold-heartedly alienate myself into nonstop work, &quot;I know my destination I&#39;m just not there.&quot;</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Take My Food Too!]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/take-my-food-too</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/take-my-food-too</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My nephew sat thereon at the glass dining table. He was like an innocent chipmunk. His puffy round cheeks, moved in circular motions as he consumed his golden brown pancakes. Kofi hadnt been eating for long. The hotcakes covered plate like a blanket on a bed, and white puffy steam gushed up the hotcakes. He saw I had been admiring him, and he wasn&#39;t pleased. Kofi was always running around the house and asking me questions about my personal life. My nephew was a happy-go-lucky kid, but that went out the window when I came.</p><p>My sister and I are inseparable. Even when she moved across the Atlantic to give my nephew a better opportunity in life, I need to join her. They&#39;ve been living in the Dumfries suburban in a lovely townhouse, in a comfortable inviting neighborhood. Their house was a magnetic force that lured me closer to it. I hurried down the parking trying to find the visitor parking, theres never enough room when you need.</p><p>&quot;Ugh, I cant believe it! Im this close to seeing my sister again, but this freaky lack of parking is getting in the way!&quot; Assaulting my leather steering wheel I bring to cry. In the corner of my eye, I watched my sisters husband step out of the white townhouse on the absolute left of the chain of homes. They were already having dinner, he was wearing his white tank top stained with scrumptious liquids.</p><p>&quot;Olivia! Come park in my spot, I will move my Toyota!&quot; he yelled as he used his hands to signal me his way. He lives his front porch and hops into his modest green car. Blrrrt, the car yawns as he ignites it. Pah, moans the vehicle as it gets up from its resting spot and moves down the driveway. I park my car in the parking lot and rush into the house, suitcase flying behind me.</p><p>&quot;Who are you maam?&quot; a young adorable boy asks me. A tear ran down my cheek as his large Bambi like eyes looked at me. I swooped him up into my arms and squeezed him with my love. We haven&#39;t had a lovely moment since. I&#39;ve been staying in his room, it must&#39;ve been a sacred place to him. From an adorable chipmunk to an aggressive grumpy cat, my nephew acted differently around me. I somewhat felt bad for being in his mom, I knew tell he loved it. Every day I stayed he would visit to annoy me. Didn&#39;t work though, he&#39;s too cute and funny to get on my nerves.</p><p>&quot;Auntie, why are you stealing my room?&quot; He asked daily.</p><p>&quot;Oh sweetheart, I&#39;m not. I&#39;m just borrowing it for a few days. Don&#39;t worry I won&#39;t make a mess.&quot;</p><p>I descended stair and walked into the kitchen. My sweetheart was eating breakfast with his mom sitting next to him. He noticed me and his smile quickly hide under a devious smirk.</p><p>&quot;Hey, Auntie, why don&#39;t you take my food since you&#39;re taking my room!&quot; He stabbed his pancake with his fork and sat up from his seat. He had an enormous grin on his face, it is as if he planned that all. My sister and I shared a laugh. I couldn&#39;t wait to tell him all this when I grew up.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Chase]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/the-chase</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/the-chase</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Andrea had finally managed to escape the office with her parcel, and hid, breathing hard, behind a dumpster in an alley, and listened as her pursuers ran past, shouting orders at each other. She could barely breath from running so hard, and she was sure they could hear her gasping for air, or even her heartbeat thudding in her own ears. But no, they ran past, and Andrea was safe... for the next couple of seconds, at least.</p><p>She glanced down at the small item in her hands. <em>This is it? This is what all this is for?</em> Carl was going to be thrilled. She, on the other hand, was furious. She&#39;d practically gotten herself killed, still <em>might</em> get herself killed... and for <em>what</em>? It was so senseless.</p><p>She was strongly tempted to just take the stupid thing and throw it in the Hudson. Let Carl rage - <em>he</em> was sitting safely at home, waiting for her to do all the dirty work for him!</p><p>Having finally caught her breath, she looked around for where to go next. Dumpster, alley, leading to streets in both directions. And a few fire escapes. She could go to the rooftops. But that was probably the first place <em>they</em> were looking.</p><p>But it was either the fire escape, or the street. Or, she could just stay here behind the dumpster and hope that nobody looked there. She was still weighing those three options when she heard the footsteps. A single set of footsteps, coming down the alleyway towards her.</p><p>Andrea figures it&#39;s too late now to run to the fire escape or the street. Not leaving in her best opinion. She zips her jacket all the way to neck length then pulls it over her nose. By now the stench of rotten leftovers and broken electronics is distracting her ability to think of an escape plan. She picked up the sounds of fingerprints on the dumpster and muffled voices, she quickly dives into the ocean of garbage out of sight. She from her rest spot she sees a crack of light piecing from a tiny opening. And just as fast as it opens it closed. They probably couldnt hand the scent unlike Andrea, shes lived her whole life with smelly men. From being crowded in a small two-bedroom apartment with three other athletic teenage brothers, to living with this cowardly snob Carl. </p><p>Carl would receive a fist full of rotten leftovers as a bonus for the o-so special parcel. She questioned this whole mission in frustration. Why is she even wasting time doing this for Carl, her deadbeat boyfriend? At the time they dated they were still in junior high. Young, in love, full withed with ambition and passion, not knowing the future would let them down.  Carl ended up becoming a cybersecurity agent and a bug firm and Andrea, well she focused on graphic design and her gymnastics scholarship. As time went on Carl became too content, he did things half-heartedly, eventually; he loved Andrea the same. Yet she stuck around why? Maybe, hell change she thought.</p><p>Eventually, he lost his job, and the rent was right around the corner. Carl was pushed to the edge, his whole life was about to flush down the drain. He was an ant about to be crushed, gaining to will to persevere, however not in the most legal way. He thought including Andrea in his scheme would help bring them closer. </p><p>After camping out for several minutes, Andrea lifted the dumpster lid and hopped out. The coast was clear. She made her way down the street, Carls apartment was only a couple blocks away. Dispute smelling like complete dog feces, she felt self-congratulatory for being able to evade her pursuers. She goes to part herself on her back when a large, thick, dark hand grabbed mine.</p><p>Lemme helps you with that, said a larger man in a black suit and tie. Andrea froze in shook, her pursuers were onto to her the whole time. Just like an octopus, she made herself disappear. In a matter of seconds, she was gone. Andrea bolted onto a heavy populated sidewalk, pushing past civilians trying to lose the last purser in the crowd. Left, Right, Right, Left, she makes unpredictable frantic turns at the edge of blocks trying to confuse him. But it&#39;s not working, as she is leaving a trail of sweat and fear behind her.</p><p>Just as hope is lost, Andrea trips on a pebble and tumbles down a hill. Crashing and falling into a pile of leaves at the local park. Apparently, that accident was enough to lose him. Andrea picks up the parcel of the ground, surprisingly still in good condition. </p><p>She arrives at her apartment looking like she was hit by a car then tossed into a landfill. She drops the parcel right next to Carls desk. He looks up from his computer to see his angry battered up girlfriend. Oh yeah! Good job baby now was a step closer to solving all our problems he says excitedly. </p><p>It better be, because youre about to have another one, Andrea says as she crosses her arms. Carl gets up and picks up the parcel, opening it to reveal another smaller box. He picks it up with a huge smile on his face. Andrea is even more frustrated, she did not risk just her life to bring Carl a little box! But as Carl stands up and knees with the box held high, Andreas angry vanishes. </p><p>Baby I understand the past few years havent been the best. Ive lost my touch but seeing you work so hard to keep us going inspired me. I want to make up for those lackluster years. Ive been secretly getting my life together, got a job, lost weight. All the things we didnt do. I love Andrea Jackson. Will you give me a chance and marry me? </p><p>Y-y-yes I do! Andrea says as she fills to room with moist passionate tears. The too hug and makeup.</p><p>Look before you get mad at me for making you go throw all that I just want to say it was all planned. Those guys are friends from my new job, I knew you would recognize them haha. This whole pursuit was inspired by our favorite movie growing up, The Chase featuring John Jones. We had so many good moments in that movie, I thought emulating it would be fun for you Carl explain as he helps Andrea slip into something less disgusting.</p><p>Its okay honey, youre going to pay for my hair, nails, spa day, and new clothes. You are going to make up for this, she says with a devious smile. Oh, Carl, youd think a gift card or a mini surprise party wouldve been a smarter idea.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blog]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/blog</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2001 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Essays]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/essays/index</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/essays/index</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2001 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Home]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/index</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/index</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2001 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Plays]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/index</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/plays/index</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2001 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poems]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/index</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/poems/index</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2001 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Shorts]]></title>
            <link>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/index</link>
            <guid>https://mkowusujr.github.io/Espressions/shorts/index</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2001 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <author>mrfriiday@gmail.com (Mathew Owusu Jr)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>